<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-alaska-gold-rush</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn99021999/1890-05-04/ed-1/?sp=5&q=Alaska+gold+rush</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>THE COLD FIELDS OF ALASKA
Statistics of the Mineral Woilth of the Ac
quisition of 1867.
AMERICA'S MOST PROFITABLE MINES
Grout Mountains ol' Mineral Wealth
A uniting Development The Need
of Go\eminent Aid in Mak
ing Explorations.
II. Kmtlty late United States Judge of
Mal a. In the Arena for Mttv.
Since the acquisition of Alaska in 1867
public attention In regard to it has boon
mainly directed to the salmon fisheries
in Its waters and to the seal rookeries in
Bohring sea. The value of the country
as a dependency has boon wholly deter
mined by the public from the rental
which the PrlbOlolT Islands yield to the
national treasury. Few references in the
intor\-oning period have boon made by
public journals and in the periodical
literature of the country to the gold-
yielding capabilities of Alaska or' to the
degree of development already reached.
The truth Is that hundreds of thousands
of intelligent Americans are profoundly
ignorant of the fact that some of the
largest and most profitable gold mining
ontorpribcs within the limits of the
United States are conducted in Alaska.
Gold in variable quantities and under
different conditions has been found in
three principal districts of Alaska the
Juneau and Douglass Island dibtrict ISO
iriilos northeast of Sltka nnd bordering
Gastcncaux channel a narrow inlet
which separates Douglass island from
the mainland the Sltka dibtrict the
quarU deposits of which nro found at
Silver Iwy n narrow tortuous arm of
the Pacific indenting BaranolT island
nnd in the valley of the Yukon river In
western Alaska. Gold bearing quart/
has albo been found nt Unga island ono
of the smaller of the Aleutian group and
SQIUO egort has been made there at de
velopment but moro of that hereafter.
-mT" At concerns the Yukon valley little at
tention 1ms boon paid by explorers nnd
prospectors to discover gold bearing
quartniul the only results bp far re
late to placer mining. At the head of
Lynn canal ono of the inner pass
ages adapted to steamer navigation
about HIM miles northeast of Sltka. Is the
ft mouth of the Ohllcatl river navigable
for canoes for n score of miles. At the
head of this canoe navigation nro three
large t'hilcatl villages and It is at this
point where commences what is known
ns the Chllcatl Portage across the range
to the head waters of the Yukon river in
British territory. The distance from
the Indian villages on the American
side of the divide to the first lake the
bource of the Yukon is about thirty
miles but the source is one of the most
dillicult in the territory yet the only
practicable ono to reach the Yukon
valley from the south. During the past
three yeatt the reports that the bars of
the Yukon and its tributaries. Stewart
and i'ellv rivers nnd Forty-Mile crook
were rich in placer gold have induced
several Alaska miners to venture across
the range at the Chllcatl crobsing and
descend these streams. Several parties
nro all known to have perished in this
perilous search for the new gold fields.
In the history of gold mining in the
states and territories no obstacle was so
stubborn that it was not finally over
come. This too will be the history oj
he tfolu" fields of western Alaska.</text>
      </result>
      <result>

	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86063615/1897-07-20/ed-1/?sp=2&q=Alaska+gold+rush&st=text&r=0.301,0.07,0.14,0.182,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>GOLD MER RAGING.
ALASICAV TfnWvS DESERTED IN THE
IILS1I l'Oll KLONDIKE.
MANY GOING WITHOUT MEANS.
MORE STOniES OF THE WEUTII
THAT II S BEEN DISCOVERED.
Captain HlKSiun, of the Excelsior,
Sa Thut Klondjke la n. Great
Place for a Man IVItU a
Icnr's Provision to
Make a StuL.e.
Port Townsend, Wash., July 19 The ex
cursion steamer Queen has arrived from
Alaska with 170 passengers, principally
tourists. Tho officers of the Queen state
that the merchants and tradesmen in both
Juneau and Sitka are closing their shops
and hastening to the new Eldorado Fifty
business men left Juneau for Daw ton City
on Julv 12, and 130 were to leave on the
16th, two das after the Queen sailed The
officers sa that by tho time tho Queen re
turns to Juneau on her return trip, nine
davs hence, there will not ba an able-bodied
man left in the town. Many men are leav
ing Juneau for tho gold fields without pro
visions or means to buy them
Tho steamer Al Kl balled for Alaska at
midnight. She carries forty horses and 1,000
sheep for Dyca, where they will be land
ed and driven across tho summit to the
Yukon vallei. Stockmen say the sheep
are the finest band ever collected off East
ern Washington ranges. They will be taken
to Circle City and Klondike and slaughter
ed. Any kind of fresh meat there sells at
50 cents per pound.
San Diego, Cal., July 19. An Interesting
letter telling of the recent trip of the
steamer Excelsior to Alaska has been writ
ten by Captain J. F. Hlggins, of the steam
er, to a friend In this city Hesajs.
"The word Klondike means Deer river,
which Is called Reindeer river on the
charts. It empties into tho Yukon fifty
miles abovo tho big river. The geographic
al position of the Junction is 76 degrees 10
minutes north latitude. 139 degrees 50 min
utes west longitude. Ronanza creek dumps
Into Klondike about two miles above the
Yukon. Eldorado is a tributary of the
Bonanza. Ther are numerous other creeks
and tributaries, the main river being 300
miles long The gold so far has been taken
from the Ronanza and Eldorado, both well
named, for the richness of the placers lz
truly marvelous. Eldorado, thirty miles
long. Is staked the whole length and as far
as worked has paid.
"As each claim Is 509 feet along the creek
bed, there is half a million to the claim.
So uniform has the output been that one
miner who has an Interest In three claims
told me that If offered his choice he would
toss up to decide. One of our passengers
who Is taking J1.000 with him has worked
100 feet of his ground and refused J200,0u0
for the remainder and confidently expects
to clean up J100.0O) nnd more. He has In a
bottle J212 from one pan of dirt. His pay
dirt while btlng washed averaged J250 an
hour to each man shoveling In Two others
of the miners who worked their own claims
cleaned up J6O0O from tho day's washing.
"There Is about fifteen feet of dirt above
DedrccK, the pay streak averaging from
four to six feet, which Is tunneled out while
the ground Is frozen Of course the ground
tal.cn out is thawed by building fires, and
when the thaw comes and water rushes In
they set their sluices and wash the dirt.
Two of our fellows thought a small bird
in the hand worth a large one In the bush
and sold their claims for Jlj.OuO, getting
JI.500 down, tho remainder to be paid In
monthly installments of J10000 each The
purchasers had no more than J3.000 paid.
They were twenty days thawing and get
ting out dirt. Then there was no water to
sluice with, but one fellow made a rocker
and in ten dais took out the J10.000 for the
first Installment. So tunneling and rotklng.
they took out J49.000 before there was water
to sluice with.
"Ot courts thebo things read like tho
story of Aladdin but fiuion is not In It</text>
      </result>
    <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1897-07-20/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Alaska+gold+rush&st=text&r=-0.267,-0.114,1.446,1.446,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>INEXHAUSTIBLE RICHES OF THE NORTHERN EL DORADO.
SEATTLE, Wash.. July 19.— The busi
ness equilibrium of Seattle was never so
disturbed as it has been by the news of the
richness of the recent Klondyke strikes.
'For forty-eight hours the telegraph offices
of this city have been thronged by people
sending messages to Eastern friends
making a request for sufficient money to
get into the new camp. The list of those
who have arranged to go includes not only
'clerks and such as work for salary, but
business and professional men of recog
nized standing and ability.
"Send me $500. Stake me enough
money to go to Klondyke. News not in
the least exaggerated," is the tenor of the
appeal flashed over the wires. Men are
t being grubstaked in tnis city to an extent
never before thought of and never before
possible. Some local bouses who are
likely to lose trustworthy and well-known
employes will be behind them in many
cases, while individual men with money
at their disposal who by reason of circum
stances cannot go are not slow to outfit
men in whom they can place unbounded
confidence.
Many amusing instances connected with
grubstakes are transpiring.- One which
will actually describe the situation had
its finale this morning early. A well
known man, honest but poor, was one of
the first stricken with the desire to go.
The information reached a friend Satur
day afternoon and shortly after the two
met. "How much do you want?" in
quired No. 2 of the Klondyke fever pa
tient. "I think about $400," was the re
spon-e. "bee me in the morning; I think
I can stake you." Sunday the two did
not meet, but early this morning they
did,, when No. 2 gave the first man a chill
that extended down the vertebra^ to the
end of his toes. "I guess that matter is j
all off," No. 2 said. "I have about decided
to go myself, and my man who is inter- 1
ested with me is also going."
It must be said that meanwhile noth-
ing is occurring which in the least de-
j tracts or discredits tho Monte Cristo-like
tales first sent out from the district. Sub- j
sequent reports not only verify but tend to
enlarge upon the first accounts. Hon.
C. H. Macintosh, Governor of the North
west Territory, comprising the districts of
j Alberta, Saskatchewan, Assinniboia and
the unorganized districts of the Yukon, i
Athabasca and all the territory east to
Labrador and Hudson Bay, arrived in j
Seattle' to-day, being en route to Regina,
the capital of tha Territory. He was seen
at the Rainier CluD.of which he is a guest,
this afternoon. When asked for an ex
pression of his views regarding the great
Klondyke district Governor Macintosh
replied:
"We are only on the threshold of the
greatest discovery 'ever made. Gold has
been piling up in all -these innumerable
streams for hundreds of years. Much of
the territory the, foot of man has .never
trod. It would hardly be possible for one
jySS exaggerate tee richness, hot only of the
Klondyke, but other districts in the Cana-
dian«"Yukon. At the same time the folly
of thousands rushing in there without I
proper means of subsistence and in utter
ignorance of the geographical conditions j
1 of the country should be kept ever in
mind. There are fully 9000 miles of these
i golden waterways in this section of the
Yukon. Rivers, creeks and streams of i
l every size and description are all pos- I
"sessed of more or less gold. I derived this j
knowledge from many old Hudson Bay
explorers, who assured me that they con
sidered the gold-bearing district next to
_ inexhaustible.
"In 1894 I made a report to Sir John
Thompson, then Premier of Canada, and
who died the same year at Windsor
Castle, strongly urging that the name
Yukon should be given to that country
by order in council and that a body of
Canadian police be established on the
river to maintain order. This was done j
j in 1&05 and the British outpost of Fort
Cudahy was founded. I have known gold
to exist there since 1889 consequent upon
a report made me by W. Ogilvie, the j
Government explorer.
Many of "-/hat will no doubt prove to be
as rich or richer streams than the Klon- i
dyke have not been explored or pros- I
pected. Among these I might mention
Dominion Creek, Hootalinqua River,
Stewart River, Liard River and a score of j
other streams comparatively unknown. j
It is my judgment and opinion that the
1897 yield of the Canadian Yukon will ex- i
ceed $10,000,000 in gold. Of course as is
the case of the Cariboo and Cassiar dis- I
tricts years ago, it will be impossible to
accurately estimate the full amount taken
out. There is now far in excess of $1,000,
--000 remaining already mined on the Klon
dyke. It is in valises and tin cans and
some of it is lying loose in saloons and
just as sacredly guarded there and appa
rently as safe as though it was in vaults.
"Already this spring we have official
knowledge of, over $2,000,000 in gold
having been taken out of the Klondyke j
THE YUKON ORDER OF PIONEERS— McQuestin, the Father of the Camp, Sits in the
Middle, With Frank Bowker, Who Has $90,003 in Gold Dost, on the Righ^
The San Francisco Call
Official Verification of the Wonderful Gold Discoveries in the Klondyke j
District Ten Million Dollars a Conservative Estimate of What
Will Be Taken Out This Year.
camps. It was shipped out, as you know, j
on the steamers Excelsior ana Portland.
Let me cite a little incident or an instance t
shewing the gold yield of some of the j
Klondyke claims. A friend of mine went j
to a dump and was looking it over, and lie j
told me that it bore the appearance of
some ones having taken and poured j
bucketfuls of gold nuggets down over the
dump. In truth, he said there appeared
to be more gold than dust. Incidentally*
I may say to you that we have data of an j
official nature which leads us to believe i
ttiat the gold output for the Rossland and
Kootenay districts for 1397 will be in excess j
of $7,000,000, including the silver yield I j
should have said, and I have no hesitancy j
in asserting that within the course of five I
years the gold yield of the three districts j
named will exceed that of either Colorado,
California or South Africa."
Governor Macintosh announced that I
the Government is seriously considering i
the construction of a railroad into the I
Yukon district. In fact, he said, it has
several corns of engineers now making
surveys.
"One route," the Governor said, "con- i
templates the operation of a line of steam
ers from Fort Wrangel up the Stickeem
R ver, which Is open to both countries,
under the Washington treaty of some
twenty-five years ago, to Telegraph Creek.
From Telegraph Creek surveyors are now
endeavoring to ascertain the feasibility of
the construction of a railway line from j
125 to 130 miles to Teslin Lake. The route
extends through scrubby timber, and has
only one or two serious obstacles. Begin-
ning with Teslin Lake, boats will be oper- j
ated along a series of lakes and rivers that j
connect with the Stewart and Pelly rivers
emptying into the Yukon. It is claimed
that no serious difficulties, that is diffi-
culties such as cannot be reasonably over- j
come, are encountered anywhere along
this route.
"1 may say in this connection that tbe
route I have just described to you would
be more than 3000 miles shorter than the
present route by way of Sl Michaels and
the YuKon and every foot of it would be
in British territory. There is another
route through Canada which has been
found possible. A railway extends from j
Calgary, Northwest Territory, over 200
miles. Then there is a trail, and a good j
one, from Edmonton to Athabasca, land
ing in the unorganized district of Atha- j
basca.* Hudson Bay boats how run over
.Athabasca La k.* down slit river of Atha- j
basca to the vicinity of McKenzie River,
where it has' been found possible with
very easy portages to reach the Porcupine
River, and thence down that stream into
the' Yukon. The Government explorer, j
Mr. Ogilvie, made an inspection of this
route several times, once in 1887. once in
1888 and in 1890 and 1891 with Mr. j
Dawson, the director-general of geological j
surveys. The White horse River route is J
also considered feasible."
The Governor leaves in the morning for I
Victoria, going thence to his capital. Re- j
gina. He comes here in reality to see one j
of his sons, who has the fever, safely off
to the Klondyke.
Discussing the Stikeem River route the j
Alaska Mining Record of Juneau in the i
issue of July 14 says:</text>
      </result>
      <result>

	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030272/1896-03-01/ed-1/?sp=28&q=Alaska+gold+rush&st=text&r=-0.172,-0.067,1.344,1.344,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>r I THE RUSH TO THE YUKON I
t i ZnOlllHCrS or A mo ciioii IN
j i k run GREAT VZACER nzqriixos
0
0f Xi rtlH In I iTnneau PripBtlat to Tackle the
t j BelRe About the Middle of March One
Immallr Knrlj HurtHaw to Get Into
t r the llmln Reqalrementi of n Froiipeetor
i Htorlen from the Alaska lnalnc
z il W JUNEAU Alaska Feb OThe rush Into tho
tI t Yukon has already begun The first party of
minors t tko tho trail lot Juncaii about tlio
1 middle of January There wore nine men lu
tho party Thin Is I nn nnuitinlly early start
for miners Ao many othera In town nro
I r getting ready for the trip Intending t tacklo
b tho range about tho middle of March Every
g Htcamer that come In from below now brings
I r n party of oldtimers and crowds of now mel
i r all anxious t Ret In and Ret to work Tho
it t Yukon country In II mot certain to bo over
1 crowded this summer surly as regards winter
t supplies unlosa largo outfits nro taken In from
t hero b tho minors
t i I From all accounts received her from BOO
4 tlons along the PaclOo coast and In the Kant
Alaska I f destined to receive a rush of people
this summer which will not bo consistent
rl t I with tho present progress and tho amount of
c4 work nowgolqg on Alaska at present ran
k support 8 many people and no more and If
I the rush pans out according t present pros
pects there Is likely to bo cons lerablo hard
Wi hip Alaska has no Industries except mining
i I nt which tho wage earner can make a decent
I 1 livelihood and unless a man has cuflldont
t meang to carry him through either In soma
Il t business orfor a seasons prospeetnl ho had
Js letter steer clear of this country It reouin
t omo capital l IUi prospect foru a mining claim
f1 I and when tho claim Isfound It requires more
f capital t open It up Gold nuggets do not
grow on bushes and It takes both 1 mans
I hands and his rockets to get tho low metal
ln this country Theres an almighty lot of
I 4t here but It Isnt to b had for tho asking
It Is perhaps timely now to tell something
t explicit about tho way of getting Into tho Yu
t kon and tho difficulties of tho trip Xo ono
should think of coming to Alaska who has not
perfect health and has not moreover u more
than ordinarily strong constitution to enable
I lilm t withstand the atmospheric nnd cllniatlo
changes In tho Yukon district tho thcrmom
ictcrhas an annual range of 180 Thcro Is a
f time In tho short summer when It ranges about
I 110 above zero and In tho winter it frequent
LII jy goes t 70 below and sometimes more
I 9 I J No ono should como to Alaska who has not
1 omo practical knowledge of quartz and placer
t
1 mining Theories nro all rlaht In their
I way and tbo theorist may stumble upon
f5 something good but It Is tho practical
prospector who gets tho Alaskan nug
Lti gets every time Every unfavorable re
i j port of Alaska mines can b traced directly I to
d seine disappointed tenderfoot who thought he
ti I could como up hero and pick the gold olf the
1 Imshes Most of them didnt like it because
i 11 they found they couldnt get nuggets as easily
f II us they could salmon berries Anybody can
I tell uold after tho smelter gets through with
It but It Isnt to easy to know where to lok
F I tor and how to timid It
I you are contemplating making the trip
I f Into tho Yukon you want t give careful confederation
i I I federation to theso thing Tho length of tlmo
t you will have to stay In tho country tho
I pmount of money It will take and tho results I
i I I which may bo attained liriefly these things
are Tlmo tlirco years money SOO roo
suits unlimited Little can b accomplished
t In less than three years stay In the Yukon
V unless tho prospector has marvelous good
luck A good part of tho first season will b
consumed In reaching tho mines Then If u
I claim Is discovered and located only prelimi
nary work can bo clone The second year tho
i claim can b opened up well and probably
I y otte money can b mado Tho third year Is
I when IH6 prospector may reasonably expect to
I I get his profits
No man ought t make tho start Into the Yu
kon basin with loss than S300 above what ho
expects t spend for the outfit which shall carry
I him through to tho diggings That Is if ho goes
In by way of Juneau and over tho pass ho wants
I to havo SiOO when ho gets to Forty Mile or
Circle City or wherever It Is he Is going I
I lie goes by the way of St Michaels and up tho
Yukon ho wants to have just the same money
Tlie read Is a long ono whichever way ho goes
t Supplies are expensive The season Is short and
fortune Is fickle Failure to find cold the first
I I lon Is likely to entail great hardship upon
L those whoso funds mire Insufficient at tho start
m Not one In a hundn makei u paying strike
the first ncnson iho trading companies In
k the Interior find market for
Ind a quick mlrkot all their
I I goods at spot nth pi ices all they refuse Ibo
I lutcly to give rf lrce Their supoly Is almost
I Invariably behind the demand These aro the
I coldblooded facts and If you havent got time
money to meot them VOlt hud better not try to
ro Into the Yukon bn in looking for a fortune
I You wont get I Hut I vouve got the money
and If yoU ore strong nud healthy and ambi
tious and aro n prm tleul prospector and If
youve got pood grit why come along Heres
tho i lace where you can make a pile Thems
I lots of It up here and such men are digging it
out every jear I Is I estimated that they dug
out In t le Yukon district In tho lust season
II upward nf SHOOOOO and that isnt a patch 01
wnats there
p I The great basin of the Yukon Is reached
I practically by hut one rcnite that by I way of
t Juneau and tho Chltkoot Pass Tills Is tho
ehcrtest quickest and cheapest route and
i the ono taken bv fully on per cent of the
J r gold seekers of tho Interior The first hun</text>
      </result>

    <result>
	    <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1898-04-09/ed-1/?sp=8&q=Alaska+gold+rush&st=text&r=-0.026,0.392,0.581,0.581,0</id>
	    <rel>1</rel>
	    <text>JUNEAT', Alaska. April 4 (by steam-
Bhip Al-Ki, via Seattle, April B).— A
horrible catastrophe, surpassing in the
number of fatalities the flooding of the
canyon last fall by the mountain lake,
nas occurred in Dyea Canyon, between
Sheep Camp and the Scales. An ava
lanche of snow and ice yesterday after
aoon swooped down the mountain,
burying alive and crushing between
forty and fifty men, and injuring nearly
is many more. There is great excite
ment as Skaguay and Dyea, and many
will leave here for the scene of the dis
ister on the steamship Australia, which
sails late f>-night for Skaguay. The
srst news of the calamity reached here
at 5 o'clock this afternoon on th»
Bteamship Discovery and the Al-Ki
came in at about 8 o'clock to-night and
;onfirmed the report.
The Al-Ki left Skaguay at 9:30 this
morning. As the fatal snow slide oc
curred at about 4 o'clock yesterday
(Sunday) afternoon only meager details
were obtainable here to-night. The
representative of The Cah whom I left
In charge at Skaguay and Dyea during
my absence chartered a tug at Skag
uay last evening to take him around
the point to Dyea and from there he
will go by horse to the place of death.
I will reach the scene to-morrow after
noon.
A telephone message was received at
Skaguay from Dyea late last night,
stating that twenty-seven bodies had
been dug out of the snow. A large force
of volunteers is at work with pick and
shovel throwing aside the snow in the
hope that it may be in time to rescue
Borne of the buried men alive. The res
cuers worked all night.
About 8 o'clock this morning another
message came by telephone from Dyea
stating that eighteen more bodies
had been excavated. If these figures
are accurate they will make a total of
forty-three dead.
The slide occurred in about the same
place where the lake of water broke
loose last fall. It was near Stone
House and over on the other side of the
canyon. John Pellett of Seattle, a pas
senger on the Discovery, left Sheep
Camp yesterday morning, a few hours
before the snow slide. He said:
"The first we heard of the accident
was last evening at Skaguay. The re
port came over from Dyea by tele
phone. I left Sheep Camp early yes
terday morning to catch the first boat
south. It had been snowing steadily
for two days up the canyon. It was a
heavy, wet snow. Great quantities of
It accumulated on the mountain sides,
and I expected some of it to fall down.
There was so much snow that I did not
Bee how it could cling to the sides of the
canyon. Great fields and mountains of
It were piled upon the top of the can
yon on both sides. There are tents and
camps all along the canyon. The men
gx» up loaded early in the morning and
come back to their camp or cache at
Sheep Camp at 11 or 12 o'clock. In the
afternoon they make another trip to
the summit or the Scales, and along
about 4 o'clock and on to 5 o'clock there
j- r*Kular crocession of men cominir
bark on the trail. That explains to me
why so many were caught and buried.
"The walls of the canyon opposite
Stone House are almost perpendicular.
A man would have only one chance In
a hundred of petting out of the way
of an avalanche there, even If he
looked up and saw It earning. It would
be a straight fall Instead of a slide. I
heard that thirty-one dead men were
taken out last night."
A little more light Is thrown on the
disaster by the situation of the trails
at Stone House. The horse trail runs
to the right of the canyon, going up
and over close to Stone House. Foot
and handsled trail Is over on th~ op
posite side and follows the course of
the river, which is considerably lower
than the horse trail, and all day Ions?
there are twenty men on the hand
sled trail to one on the horse trail. I
have seen 100 men on this trail within
a distance of fifty yards, going and
coming. Nearly opposite Stone House,
on the brow of the canyon, is a glacier.
Its walls of ice, beautiful as emerald
and sapphire in' the sunshine, an im
aginary cathedral of the skies, stand
exposed in June as well as in January-
It does not melt away the y?ar round.
Mountains of snow crown this glacier
during the winter. This is the point
from which the avalanche came.
A small snow slide which occurred
shortly before the big avalanche buried
two or three men who were encampc-d
along the trail. While those on the trail
were hard at work endeavoring to ex
tricate the unfortunates the monster
avalanche swept down the mountain
side, crushing the tents pitched along
the trail and enveloping scores of men,
the majority of whom were endeavoring
to assist those who had met with mis
fortune in the previous smaller slide.
The injured gold-seekers who have
been rescued are terribly lacerated, and
it is feared that a number of them will
die. As soon as the news of the calam
ity was made known along the trail
men hurried to the scene from Dyea
and other points, and with shovels,
picks and even pans and pails toiled
to extricate the unfortunates. Sheep
Camp was soon left without an inhabi
tant, as every one from there to the
scales was soon on the scene.
The sight was an awful one, for there
in a state of terrible excitement, which
increased as the bodies were uncovered,
were brothers, fathers, sons and friends
anxiously digging, trembling lest the
next body they uncovered should. be
that of a loved one. As in the rush to
the gold fields, but few men, even
though traveling together, went to the
trouble of inquiring as to the names
of their companions, the greater num
ber of the dead have not been Identi
fied, and those who have been taken
out alive are so benumbed and dazed
that they can hardly tell who had been
in company with them.
The roar of the avalanche could be
distinctly heard at Sheep Camp and as
far as Canyon City, situated about six
miles south of the fatal spot.
Seventeen men. all members of the
Chilkoot Transportation Company,
started over the trail on Sunday morn
ing and had about time to reach the
Scales when the terrible slide occurred.
None of them have since been seen,
and none of their bodies have been re
covered. It Is feared the entire party
was caught in the slide and killed.
There were a good many tents covered
up beyond the reach of rescuers and
numbers of bodies will never be re
covered until the spring sun thaws
away their snow graves.</text>
    </result>


            <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85038615/1905-04-02/ed-1/?sp=31&q=Alaska+gold+rush&r=-0.335%2C0.126%2C1.406%2C0.916%2C0&st=text</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>PRICE FIVE CENTS
rwn HRILLING and MlMBfis tlie call
M now being trumpeted'byTatiana, the
Eldorado in Alaska.' Already thou?
sands of frenzied seekers after gold are there.
"For fortunes beyond the dreams of.ava
rice are being garnered by placer mines along
the streams in that locality.
As much as $ioo a pan has.been washed
out in this new district. How startling these
figures are to miners may be judged from'the
fact that, ground averaging 40 cents to the
pan is considered a bonanza, and ip cents a
pan is regarded as big pay.
During the last winter, in spite of the
fact that the ground was frozen, one claim
averaged $1000 in pay dirt a day, and a num?
ber of claims changed hands at $60,000 each.
Within the last twelve months 4000
miners from the Klondike have rushed to the
new fields.* They were the first to hear the
news. All durW.g the winter hundreds strug?
gled thither over snow and ice. Indications
point to a remarkable rush northward from
Seattle this string.
Fairbanks, the centre of the Tatiana
region, consisted a year ago of a few log
cabins. To-day it is a prosperous city of over
three thousand people, with all the conven?
iences of modern city life.
AS SOON as boats are able to navigato the
inland streams of Alaska, a great summer
rush to Tanana is expected to begin. Re?
ports from Seattle state that gold-seekers
aro crowding therj from all parts of the country.
A surprisingly large number are outfitting as
though they had been in mining regions beforo nnd
knew how to arrange for the long and tiresomo trip
by steamer, dog team and afoot. 1
Freight charges from Seattle to Dawson in
eummer average over $7d a tori, and as much moro
from .Dawson to Fairbanks, so that the cost of tak?
ing along an extensive equipment is considerable.
It is estimated that the Tanana region pro?
duced $1,500,000 in gold last year, when tho num?
ber of miners was insignificant, compared with the
great army that will camp alonar its streams this
season.
Before news of tho rich'finds penetrated beyond
,the silent forests, pioneer prospeotorj had quietly
taken out a quarter of a million in yellow metal
flakes.
Until the new trails were broken aud in use,
Tanana was not an easy section of Alaska to reach
or leave, and travelers along that way wero scarce?
consisting principally of Indians hunting game or
stray prospectors nosing about for gold.
Situated on tho Tanana river, tho town of
Fairbanks is 150 miles southeast of tho point of
juncture pf that river with'the mighty Yukon; Daw
eon, in the Klondike, is 500 miles away to the oast
ward by sledgo trail, and to the south Valdez, on
the coast, is 5?i miles distant.
Discoverers of gold along tho Tanana wore not
inclined to shout tho glad tidings to the world.
Among those patiently .washing dift there dur?
ing the fall of 1002 wa*'a secretivo individual, a
Mexican, known as Pedro,
Pedro, like the others, lived in a little hut. His
bed was a blanket; chairs and table Avere simply
blocks of -wood. He had little use for the cabin, ex?
cept as a placo to sleep and store his provisions.
All the long arctic days ?ho searched soil along
the streams for gold, usually alone in the vast wil?
derness. At other places w? re other men'similarly
engaged, but they, too, were'there for business and
had little time for sociability.
Ono day Pedro made" a big strike. Ho found
gold that turned out $100 to, the. pan. Pedro was
a rich man. Then he went away to the couth. But
he didn't spread the news-?he was faithful to tho
miners left behind.
Others, too, were lucky. Stray prospectors
came that Avay andimmediately'located claims.- It
seemed as if somo had smelled the good news from
distant camps.,
For months this handful of men struggled
fiercely to wash all the gold they could before tho
mad rush they knew was coming, sooner or later.
First to arrivo Avere some steamboat men Avho
had ascended the river with supplies for tho trading,
post just opened at Fairbanks. These men heard
of the marvelous new field and promptly staked
claims there.
Among them was an energetic Japanese named
Wada, Avho, like others of his race, had been in
many mining camps of the far North.
For some reason, as soon as ho had ctaked his
claim and learned of the richness of the region,
Wada started out on a long, lono tramp over the
snow, with a dog team drawing his ipplies, for
Dawson) BOO mi lea away.
No trail liad been broken -or at least half the
distanco, butWada. plunged along, helping the dogs
and Making from fifteen to twenty-five inilos a day.
He wns tho first to bear the news of Tanana'a
wealth to Bawsou, and minors of the older Klondike
region immediately Avent wild.
This was in the Avintor of.lOO'i?an exception?
ally cold season, even in Alaska.
Without waiting for spring, -.rimers hurried off
in hundreds for a 6U0-mile journey over snow and
ice, and through a.roadless -yilderness, in a tem?
perature from 50 to CO degreed below ?ero.
Hastily authoring what supplies thoy could,
some left Bawson in small sleighs drawn by horses,
others with ?log teams; but the greater number
hurried along on foot, drawing their sleda them-,
'selves.
It was a mad rush for g?ld^:3ir?ny.reached tha
?new field before spring, ?but hundreds of others
came'toiling in all during tho sunom?f.
"When the majority arrived thoy, found the best
claims'already taken, a shortago of, supplies facing
them, and discouragement in tho air.
Wada had returned with the rush. When some
of the men realized their position, they brga?niged'
a miners' meeting and decided to hang the' Jap.
A rope Avas found, and Wada was about to be
strung tip, when ho produced a copy ?f a Seattle
newspaper, showing that he had onco saved the
lives of many whalers, ico-impriaoned in the Arctic
Ocean by tramping overland from Point Barrow to,
St. Michael in dead of winter.
This saved his life, but "Wada Avas driven from
the region to which he had invited tho rush.
In spite of their first disappointment, tho new?
comers spread out and set to work. At this time
gold was only known to exist along one creek. Soon
it" was found along a dozen creek's.
In the spring tho rush from Bawson continued
by steamboat. Olairas were located in overy direc?
tion. Now hundreds who arrived late, or Avho found
that thoir claims did not pay, ar.o working as labor?
ers for tho moro fortunate.
In a little Avhilo, too, all thb surface gold had
been panned, so that it became noces?ary to work
the underground strata by machinery.
When'tha Klondike Avaa struck, the only method
known of thawing the frozen ground for sinking
ehafta and running tunnela was to build Avood fires
on the surface, scrapo away the earth as far as it
had thawed, build other fires and keep this tedious
process up indefinitely.</text>
      </result>


    <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90059523/1899-10-15/ed-1/?sp=21&q=Alaska+gold+rush&st=text&r=-0.275,-0.078,1.551,1.551,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>ST. MICHAELS, Alaska, Sopt. 15.—
The most remarkable gold mining at
present In the world, if not in the entire
history of gold mining, is that now in
progress at and about Cape Nome, on
Norton Sound, Behring Sea, Alaska, sit
uated about 225 miles north and west
of the mouth of the Yukon river, or 135
miles from this point. Gold was first dis
covered on Snake river last fail, and
during the earlier portion of this season.
Cape Nome district had acquired con
siderable repute as a gold producer, and
not a few miners from the Yukon river
f Lx r\* rfi^*?--.".^rrT _/^ t 1" "^"^/^^^=k_.^^\!l\ V V S"^'^
new v ?^p. A^f,
MAP SHOWING LOCATION OF THE GOLDEN SANDS, AND ILLUSTRATING METHODS OF THE MINERS.
country, many of them stranded here,
f went over to Nome and either staked
such claims as they could get, or secured
work as they could find It. Much com
plaint was made that claims had been
taken by persons holding powers of at
torney, their principals not being present
in person, and in June the Cape Nome
district had become so unpopular 'hat
reports were circulating to the effect that
the whole thing was a "fake" foisted on
the public by the transportation compa
nies to Improve their business.
Whatever of truth there may have been
In these stories Is now of small import,
for in June or early July, some one of
the stranded miners tenting on the beach,
as the only unclaimed space, accidentally
discovered gold in the sand at his feet.
He told his story quickly among his
stranded friends, and soon all the unem
ployed were at work on the beach with
any and all kinds of tools that would
dig. Their success was such that within
a few days men who had work on
claims along the creek at $10 a day and
board threw up their jobs and took to
the beach, expecting to earn, and actual
ly earning in many instances, as much in
an hour as they had earned in a day.
Never had such easy mining brnn heard
Df, never had it been found so unex
pectedly and so opportunely, and it was
•lot long before everything else was 2
serted for the seashore, and even wo
olen and boys of 10 or 12 years were to bo
found as busy in the sand as the men
were.
Since the discovery the number of j
"beach combers," as they are called, has I
steadily increased, and today is presented
the strange' sight of hundreds of miners I
rof both sexes and all ages and condl-
".ions strung out along the beach for a
rlozen miles or more.
For miles to the west of Cape Nome the
oeach runs straight away In a strip of
;lde land, varying from forty to sixty
!eet in width between high and low water
mark, extending up to the "tundra" cr
black alluvial soil, which is from three
to five feet higher than the beach proper.
All of this tundra, ard all the territory
along the creeks and rivers east and west j
for thirty or forty miles and back into j
the mountains for ten or twelve miles had
been staked, but on the long strip of tide i
lands no man had a better claim than j
another, or could have, under the tide-
land laws, and here the grand army of
gold seekers camped, and in very short
order had converted the barren strand
Into a site of tremendous and enthusiastic
Industry. At the same time business of
all kinds began to respond to the boom
i from the beach, and the usual collection
of gambling hells, saloons and dance
halls went Into operation. At present it
t ls estimated that 1,000 to 1,200 miners are
at work on the beach, extending west for
twenty miles. All these work with rock
_ ers, and they occupy just as much ter
ritory to the man or group as can work
It It is not unusual for one small square
bit of beach to pan out $10 to $15 an hour,
but, of course, the space is soon exhaust
ed and the lucky digger must move to
another snot.
This beach deposit of gold Is as yet
an unsolved problem. By some It Is claim
ed that the gold In the sand, which is
entirely "dust," has been washed out
from the tundra by the waves at high
tide and deposited through hundreds of
years in the sand. It is found here now
from two to five feet below the surface In
the drift, and so plentiful that the miner
who does not find It In paying quantities
is the exception. On the other hand,
there are some who claim that the gold
is washed in from the sea, and that the
real field or "mother lode," so to speak.
Is to be reached and developed by dredg
ing. There may be something in this
theory, but the other seems to be the
more tenable, "-.ark'jpi^eya^fa^
The beach to the east of Cape Nome
makes no such gold showing as does the
beach to the west, owing to the existence
of a long reach of water or "lagoon,"
which lies a short distance back from
the sea and parallel with It. Gold deposits
along the creeks the interior are quite
as rich In one direction as the other.
The headquarters of the Cape Nome
territory is Anvil City—so named from
the shape" of the mountain above It—at
the mouth of Snake river, although Nome
City is the postofflce. While the city pos
sesses a number of frame houses, tents
are the prevailing shelter, and prices for
commodities are pretty much as they are
In all mining towns. Notwithstanding
this is one of the most' accessible mining
towns on earth, as ships from any part
of the world may come up to its very
doors, making due allowances for no har
bor, and -much delay between ship and
shore in bad weather. Meals are from
•$1.50 to $2.50 each; a bed In a tent, $1.50;
plain drinks, 50 cents each; beer, 50 cents
per glass, and other things in proportion,
including a mutton chop at $I.2s—and, by
the way, these are not much in excess of
prices at first-class places ln New York
city. Copper plate for use In rockers is
worth Its weight In silver, and one miner
who had no copper substituted silver dol
lars for It, sixty-four of them being re
quired to properly plate his rocker, which,
added to the first cost of $20, made it
somewhat expensive, even for this local
ity. Labor in the mines Is worth from $8
to $10 a day and board, and even carpen
ters, about the only other class of labor,
are paid $1.50 and hour and board them
selves. As the days In summer are from
eighteen to twenty-four, hours long, a
carpenter can put In a lot of spare time.
Everybody has money, and as many who
have It are not used to It, they are lav
ishing their earnings by day on gambling,
liquor and dance halls at night. Gam
bling takes the bulk of the dust, and
every species of game is represented in
Anvil City.
As to what amount of geld is being
taken out, there Is no means of determin
ing. It is known that not more than $200,
--000 in all have been shipped by steamer,
and $100,000 of that has gone out within
the past week. The beach mining is re
ported to be turning out about $30,000 a
day, but this in the nature of things can
not continue, and when it is exhausted
these men will go to work on the numer
ous claims lying back from the sea and
along the creeks. Here the gold is found
In very rich deposits, the claim of Linde
burg- Co., on Anvil Creek, turning out
over $1,000 an hour ($25,000 in twenty-four
hours),. one nugget recently found being
worth $312. Another claim, owned by Dr.
Kettlesen, in one day cleared* up $9,000,
and so the stories go. One may hear al
most any kind of a fairy tale, and while
some cf them are exaggerated the fact
remains that just now every man in the
district has a pocket full of dust and
heart full of hope, and there are no dead
brokes In- Anvil City. "What the condi
tions will be a year hence will not be
known until then, and cannot be pre
dicted.
Nov. 1 communication with the outside
world will be completely shut off for sev
en month's at least, and only a few of
(he people now in the Cape Nome district
are fixed with either food or shelter for
the sever!- of the climate, though those
who are prepared with houses to live in
and sufficient food and fuel can not only'
pass the winter comfortably, but can do
more or less work.
There are very few so well eff as this,
however, fuel being scarcer than food,
but among the "beach combers" a novel
plan will be adopted. Parties of four,
six or eight will organize for winter op
erations by securing a large tent, spread
ing ii over the ground they propose to
work In, and there they, will set up house
keeping. The canvas will.be protected on
the outside from the weather in every
way possible, and stoves will be kept go
ing on the inside, so that the tent will not
only be comfortable to live and to work
in, but it will never freeze in there, and
the mining can go on quite as satisfac
torily as if the balmy spring were the
only season known in tho Cape Nome dis
trict A groat rush is expected in the
spring, but, as has been stated, there are
no claims unstaked anywhere within
thirty or forty miles of Anvil City, and
what lies beyond those limits is pracfical
ly unknown. But, according to the tales
of prospectors, as far beyond as Cape
Prince of "Wales, 2:*5 miles, gold has been
found along the creaks in quantities that
would pay from $10 to $50 per man par
day if panned by an expert.
Claims are offered for sale—a claim be
ing twenty acres—at prices from $50,000
to $150,000, and there are, of course, at
this time not many takers at those, fig
ures, but they are expected In the spring
with the rush.</text>
      </result>

    <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88086023/1914-03-11/ed-1/?sp=4&q=alaska+gold+rush&r=-0.092%2C0.467%2C0.671%2C0.437%2C0&st=text</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>None</text>
      </result>

    <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87062014/1936-03-31/ed-1/?sp=2&q=alaska+gold+rush</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>LATE DR. WHITING'S
RELICS ARE TO GO
UNDER HAMMER
Seattle.—Romantic old
mementoes of Alaska’s roar
ing gold rush days, the rel
ics which the late Dr. F. B.
Whiting numbered among
his choicest treasures, will
go under the hammer at
Bushell’s Auction House.
The rifle which Dr. Whit
ing stopped the historic
strike of railroad workers,
and the steering wheel and
port and starboard running
lights of the old steamer
Portland, which brought
the first ton of gold from
Alaska to Seattle, are am
ong the articles to be auc
tioned.
There is a large collection
of Alaskan and Chinese cur
ios and art objects, oriental
rugs, furniture for eight
rooms and a four-poster bed
in which the present King
of England is reported to
have slept in while visiting
Canada.
Dr. Whiting, famed sour
dough and surgeon of the
Alaska gold rush, was fea
tured by RexBeaeh in “The
Iron Trail.” He died recent
ly at his home in Seattle.
Newspaper advertising
will develop new business
for you.
I I
Weather Today
(U. S. Weather Bureau)
Fair skies with tempera
tures above normal were
observed thruout Alaska
the western Canadian pro
vinces this morning. An
extensive high barometer
is centered over the Yukon
Territory while low baro
meter is observed central
near the end of the Aleut
ian Islands.</text>
      </result>


    <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86075258/1947-04-09/ed-1/?sp=5&q=alaska+gold+rush&st=text&r=-0.285,-0.079,1.571,1.571,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Prospectors Are U. S. Soldiers
FAIRBANKS, ALASKA. There
is a new gold rush in Alaska which
rivals in enthusiasm, if not in rich
strikes, the famous rush of '49.
Today's prospectors are soldiers
stationed in Alaska. Their gold rush
is sponsored by the USO and is
classed as off-duty recreation. But
that doesn't keep the G.I. "sour
doughs" from hoping to strike it
rich.
Confronted by soldiers freshly ar
rived from the United States for
postwar duty and demanding "the
shortest way to an undiscovered
gold mine," the USO leased eight
old mining claims near Fairbanks.
There the off-duty miners pan for
gold and dream of the day they be
come millionaires.
USO hostesses, most of them na
tive Alaskans, drive the soldiers as
far as possible over rough mountain
roads in station wagons. On the last
part of the trip to the claims, the
G.I.s have to pack their pans and
shovels through the gorges just as
the old-timers did.</text>
      </result>


	<result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87062014/1936-01-23/ed-1/?sp=7&q=alaska+gold+rush&st=text&r=-0.136,-0.163,1.139,1.484,0</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text>None</text>
      </result>


    <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1926-07-19/ed-1/?sp=19&q=alaska+gold+rush&st=text&r=-0.031,0.123,0.488,0.635,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Manager Saw Lively .Times asScrapper
in Butte and as Scale Boy in Saloon
During Alaska Gold Rush
BY JACK KEARNS.
I LEARNED a lot about socking from Dal Hawkins, as I remarked before.
Then in quick order I fought the best men of that tiinc. Among
them were Mose La Fontise,. Kid Fredericks, Kid Parker, the vege
tarian from Denver; Morris Thompson, Adian Joe Gregg and Rufe Turner.
Rufe was a hard hitter. He was the brother of old Charley Turner, negro
middleweight of considerable fame. Rufe and I went to it like wild men
until the ninth round, when, from a reclining position on my spine, l
mumbled the sad fact that there was at least one man in the world who
was a little better than Young Kearns. I think that was the hardest bout
of my whole career. Great man, Rufe Turner. t
I had a lot of respect for Indian Toe Gregg. He could fight. First I
managed him and fought him. Then I fought him and managed him. It
depended on the town we were in. When fighting material was scarce,
Indian Joe was my hated rival, and we fought for the best-part of the
town hall receipts.
Tou would Imagine that wo would
be inclined to spare each other and
all things like thit. But let me tell
you that no fights ever were fought
with more earnestness. Youth again.
Once in, the ring, we forgot about
the future. Fighting pride always
drove us dne, and if you ever chance
across me in your travels, you might
notice a slight thickness of my ears.
Those are lovable mementoes of the
sincerity with which Indian ffoe
Gregg and Young Kearns undertook
to please the yaps of the erosa-road
town.
Butte Was An Open Town.
I drifted into Butte. Mont. It was
a ball of fire. Anything went. Open
town and protect yourself at all
times. Charley Clark was the big
shot. He was the son of the million
aire copper king. He loved horses,
fighting dogs, fighting cocks, and,
most of all. fighting men. He’d im
mediately send for a boxer when
little tin ears dropped into town,
arrange a bout and pull it off at the
Nine Mile Roadhouse. He’d hang up
the purse, referee the bout and buy
wine for the crowd, afterward, most
of them having been driven to the
roadhouse battle ground in carryalls,
huckhoards, Butte sea going hacks,
bicycles, and even in ore dumpcarts.
I fought Jack Clifford for Clark
and I won. Then I took on Gens.
King. Dave Holly and Jolly Regers,
a big tall negro who had been kiss
ing all their chins with his terrible
right. They thought they had me
whipped before I started. Jolly was
backed with their last dollar. We
fought In the old Sutton Opera House.
I made up my mind that the only
way for me to beat this fellow was
to put all that T had into* an early
rush. I always believrd In that sys</text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>

  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-cloquet-fire</id>
    <results>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84024827/1918-10-13/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Cloquet+Fire+Minnesota+forest+train&st=text&r=-0.205,-0.071,1.41,1.41,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>being sent to the Belgian towns
ulong the German frontier.
VISITED BY
T
FOREST FIRE SWEEPS TOWNS
AND VILLAGES, FARMS AND
HAMLETS FROM MAP AND HUN
DREDS OF PEOPLE ARE MISSING
AS RESULT OF FLAMES
1 i
II Unl
MINNESOTA
HOLOCAUS
the British people in this hour than
any commission to arrange lor cva.-u
DULUTH, Minn, Oct. 13 Hun-jation. Events In the past week, par-
dreds of oeoule are reported missing.! ticularly the sinking of th Leinster.
cities and towns have been wiped eut,lhave steeled British hearts against a
scores after ,corM of farm, hapve been compromiRe.
fire sweat, an the fate of the po
iple in a large area of northwestern
i j t
iwhich carried everything before them
last night.
The loss of life cannot be computed
'until reports begin to trickle in from
itown, wn08e communications were cut</text>
      </result>
	  
    <result>
		<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84024827/1918-10-13/ed-1/?sp=6&q=Cloquet+Fire&st=text&r=0.237,0.462,0.402,0.523,0</id>
		<rel>1</rel>
		<text>FOREST FIRES
MENACE CITIFS
OF MINNESOTA
(Continued rro-n Tp.ee One)
"preadinr blaze was at Shaw, where
the train whizzed over burning cul
verts. Grand Rapids was reported to be
burning last night, but ns all wires
were down the report could not be
verified. Cass Lake, threatened by
fire at 5:20 p. m.. made no later re
port a"d heavy loss there was con
sidered probable.
Ppeci.il trains waited to carry the
peonle of Two Harbors out of the
fliimes. which at midii'vt were creen
in'j: ur to the town, proving too stronrr
for efforts of hundreds of fire-fighters.
When the las of four Greit North
ern trains pulled out of Cloquet list
nlrht, carrying away the last SO in
habitants, every building in that city
was ablaze except the railway station.
Nine thousand people escaped after
Champion broadens
v athletic training
i" Johnny Kilbane, featherweight
champion and now an athletic in
structor for the army, is one of
the instructors who are taking a
two-weeks course of advanced train
ing for instructors at a Southern
camp. The object of the course is to
give the men a better knowledge of
anatomy, physiology and other mat
ters that will broaden their knowl
edge in training methods, -tilbane
shows his customary spirit in want
ing to make himself more valuable
to Uncle Sara.
the Great Northern canceled other
service to go to their rescue. The
fourth train left the town at 10:30 last
nicht It was composed of freight
cars- ti ilAl'Jk
(Py Review Leased Wire)
DULUTH. Minn.. Oct. 12. Ij
!mh and Superior, are tonight the
hub of the wor3t chain of rorest fires
in the history of northern Wisconsin
and Minnesota, Conflagrations, fanned
to fury by a wind storm have destroy
ed hundreds of thousands of dollars
worth of property in the area between
Two Harbors, north of here; Moose
Lake, Brainerd, Finlayson and Ash
land. Hundreds of persons are home
less. Blazing brands have fallen in Du
luth and Superior. Buildings in the
outskirts of these twin cities have
caught fire. The rire departments and
home guards forces have responded
continuously to calls for help since
this morning.
A dozen or more persons have been
twenty settlers' homes had been
burned.
DULUTH, Minn., Oct. 12. Cloquet
was partly wiped out by the rorest
fires late today and 9000 refugees are
in Duluth and Superior, saved from
Cloquet, Arnold, Hermantown and sev
eral other smaller towns near Duluth
were also wiped out.
Hundreds are reported dead.
DULUTH. Minn., Oct. 12 The en
tire country north of Lake Superior
between Duluth and Two Harbors, is
in flumes. Fires are raging on the
outskirts of this city, menacing prop
erty so seriously tuat t!ie hems guards
ltd Fourth re-!mnt of militia have
been ca'.ied out. Many tettlers have
eeu turned cut anl everj' farm ia
the district threatened. A fire is
ia;ii! at Cass Lake, where several
'ives are reported to have been lost.
SURROUNDED BY FIRE.</text>
    </result>

	<result>
		<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86063381/1918-10-14/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Cloquet+Fire</id>
		<rel>0</rel>
		<text>None</text>
    </result>

    <result>
		<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030431/1918-10-14/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Cloquet+Fire&r=-0.108%2C0.162%2C0.625%2C0.407%2C0&st=text</id>
		<rel>1</rel>
		<text>800 TO 900 ARE
PROBABLY DEAD
IB FOREST FIRE
Duluth and Superior Men
aced by Flames Now Un
der Control.
THOUSANDS OF REFUGEES
Humors Are Circulated That
Disaster Was Caused by
Enemy Agents.
nilLUTH, Minn.. Oct. 13. With prob
ably between 100 and 900 persona dead,
thousands homeless and -without cloth
big; and -with property damage mount
Ins Into millions of dollars, whole sec
tions of northern Wisconsin and Min
nesota tlmberland to-night are smoul
dering. Are stricken areas, with charred
ruins of abandoned, depopulated towns.
The bodies of 196 victims lie In
Duluth morgues. Hundreds more along;
the roads leading- to Duluth and
Superior lie where, lacy fell when over
taken by the fire.
Twelve thousand homeless and pennl
Ie?s refugees, all In need, more or less, of
medical attention, are quartered In hos
pitals, churches, schools, private homes
and In the armory here, while doctors
and nurses sent from surrounding com
munities attend them, and nearly every
able bodied man In the city has been
conscripted to fight the flames, which
now are reported to be dying away.
Incendiaries Driven Away.
Reports that the holocaust resulted
from the work of enemy agents were
circulated here to-night. Definite con
firmation was not available, but Incen
diaries were driven away from a local
shipyard when the fires In Duluth and
Superior were at thefrhitght: according
to F. J. Loncren, Fire Marshal, and
other city and State officials.
Beports reaching here by courier told
of widespread destruction, but It was
evident that In most Instances the fury
of the flames waa spent. Duluth and
Superior are In no further danger. Vlr-'
glnla la safo and Bralnerd was un
touched. However, peat bog fires now
are said to menaco the latter city. Ber
jntdjl reported only a small lose.
Oreatest loss of life and property
damage are believed to have occurred In
the Cloquet region, where a number of
towns have been destroyed and all semi
rural settlements virtually wiped out.
Warned by Forest Itanger.
Albert Mlchaud, a special policeman,
told a tragio story, of the burning of
Cloquet and of the mad rush of its
residents to escape.
"At 6 o'clock last night a forest
ganger gave warning that unless the
wind died down the townspeople would
have to flee," said Mlchaud. "A thick
pall of smoke hung aver the town and
at 7 o'clock the special trains were
called.
"The scene at the station was In
describable. There came a rush of wind
and the entire town was in flames. The
trains pulled out with the fires blar
ing closely behind them. Women wept
and. clung to their children while others
cried frantically for their missing ones.
The flames licked at the cars. Windows
In the coaenca were broken by the
beat."
Cloquet had about 7,600 population.
More than 4,700 persona were brought to
Duluth and Superior from there alone.
Information brought In by rescue parties
Indicated that nearly 100 bodies have
k..n ktinH An miH, leadfnif to Duluth.
Beveral burned automobiles filled with
bodies were passed by the rescuers.
The town of Twig, on the Miller trunk
road, was wiped out. Other towns re
rorted as being entirely destroyed In
clude Rice take, Brookston, Brevator.
Corona, Adolph. Thompson, Arnold,
Adjutant-General W. F. Rhlnow. St
Paul, supervising rellet worK, esumaiea
to-night that more than 300 Uvea were
lost In Moose Lake and Its Immediate
vicinity.
Duluth and Superior were not defi
nitely out of danger until to-day. Trop
eity damage wrought yesterday will
total more than a million dollars.
Automobile parties dashed through a
wall of flame to rescue 200 tuberculosis
natlAntM at 4ih Tdnn.mlnf Ranltarlum.
which was partially destroyed. The pa
tients were tanen oui who sjrcaiem aun
culty, fire having partially cut off the
retreat, but It waa said to-night prob
ably none would suffer ill effects.</text>
    </result>

	<result>
		<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042243/1918-10-14/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Cloquet+fire&st=text&r=-0.283,-0.163,1.433,1.433,0</id>
		<rel>1</rel>
		<text>LARGE SECTION OF NORTHERN
FOREST SWEPT BY ONE OF MOST
DISASTROUS BLAZESJNHISTORY
Dangerous Pockets Reported North and North­
east of Duluth—Relief Work Starts Under
State Authorities.
Duluth, Minn., Oct. 14.—A large section of northern Minne­
sota today was a smoldering ruin with hundreds of bodies of men,
women and children strewn about the country side as a result of
forest fires which swept this region Saturday and Sunday. Latest
estimates place the death lists at 1,000. Hu,ndreds are more or
less seriously burned thousands are destitute and homeless, and,
I the property loss will reach many millions. A dozen cities were
destroyed.. The worst blazes were at Moose Lake, Turtle River
and Cloquet. At Moose Lake it is estimated at least 400 perished
in the flames. Although countless small fires were burning
I throughout the district today, and the more serious blazes died
down during the night, a revival of the 70-mile gale of Saturday
would add further horrors and add to the horror.
Begin Relief Work.
Relief work begun Saturday under Adjutant General Rhinow
and Governor Burnquist is progressing rapidly. The heaviest loss
reports come from Moose Lake, where relief parties are finding
scores ot bodies heaped in piles, burned to a crisp. There is every
indication, General Rhinow said today, that the loss of life in the
vicinity of Moose Lake, Turtle River and Lawler will be greater
than first estimated. During the night most of the bodies strewn
along the roads were brought to Moose Lake. Late yesterday one
company of men reached Lawler, a small village northeast of
Moose Lake. Four buildings mark all that is left of the town. To­
day there is little wind, and it is hoped all fires will be under control
by nightfall.
Dangerous fire pockets are reported north and northeast of
Duluth.
A dangerous fire is reported in the vicinity of Schultz Lake,
a rummer resort 25 miles northeast of here. All means of com­
munication have been destroyed. People familiar with the district
say there is little chance of loss of life.
Residences Obliterated.
Charred ruins marked the ravages of the fire which swept
into Duluth, destroying hoiiies in Woodland, Lakeside and Lester
Park, within the city limits. Back of Duluth the villages of
Adolph, Munger, Five Corners, Barney, Grand Lake, Maple Grove
and Twig, which were thriving communities Saturday morning,
are almost obliterated today. Further west Carlton, Cloquet,
Brookston, 'Brevator, are recognizable only by sign posts. Pike
Lake and Pine Hill are no more, tfhile to the south the Moose Lake
district is still a smoldering ruin.
Thousand Homeless.
From these points thousands-of homeless persons have arrived,
here, and points further sjtnith, while many seriously burned have
been removed to hospitals in St. Paul and Minneapolis.
Over virtually every foot of the fire swept district the devasta­
tion was complete. The few farm buildings left .standing over
approximately ten thousand square miles in Minnesota are the only
things left from the catastrophe.
One Hundred Buildings Destroyed.
Persons who have visited the burned over district declared
today there is no way to place the monetary estimate on the loss.
The fire loss to Duluth is placed at approximately $750,000.
Nearly 100 buildings have been destroyed bx the flames.
FORTY-TWO BODIES IN FIRE.
Aitkin, Minn.. Oct. 14.—The bodies of 42 fire victims found
in and near Aitkin are in local morgues, and official reports from
searchers indicated a score or more »bodi)s are still to be brought
here.</text>
    </result>

	<result>
		<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87057262/1918-10-14/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Cloquet+Fire&st=text&r=-0.216,-0.072,1.432,1.432,0</id>
		<rel>1</rel>
		<text>"I thought they might be alive,"
Jones said, "but when I lifted them
th«lr flesh fell away and only the
bones were left."
Five Great Fires.
TfUI/UTH, Minn. Oct 14.—Five for-
8Weeplng'the
timber district
of Wisconsin and Minnesota have
killed over 200 persons and done mil
lions of dollars of damage in the last
thirty-sl* hours, it was estimated to
day. The cause of the fires was un
determined, hut lncendarlsm is sus
pected.
Fourteen towns are reported razed
with thousands homeless as a result
of the blaze which eclipses historic
fires of this district.
Early today the fires were reported
checked, but still dangerous.
First fires were reported Saturday
in peet hogs, seventy-five mileB east
United Press
War Summary
1,533rd day of the war.
Peace offensive front—American
press and public are unreservedly
opposed to an armistice.
British newspapers scoff at Ger
many's reported "democratization"
and question the sincerity
reply to President Wilson.
Semi-official announcement Is made
that France is determined not to
negotiate with "Germany until her
power to do harm Is completely
ended."
Italian newspapers and clergymen
counsel against "German peace
traps."
From the North sea to Douia—The
British have carried their line for
ward until it practically parallels the
line of the Haute-^Deule canal to
Doual.
From Doual to LaFere—British
troops yesterday repulsed another
series of strong German counter at
tcaVs in various sectors, particularly
on a wide front north of LeCateau.
The British gained ground on both
sides of Douai and approached to
within seven miles of Valenciennes.
The British and Americans are
apparently in touch with the out
works of the "Valenciennes line"
south to LeCateau.
From LaFere to Verdun—The Ger
mans are being pushed back on this
between the Ar-
gonne
I Americans are encountering stiff re
sistance. After driving the enemy
from the St. Gobain massif, Laon an4
LaFere, the French have reached the
general line of Courbes, Aulnois,
Gizy, Sissone, LaMailmaison and Bail
ham. To the eastward, the French
and Americans have practically
cleared the Alane bend, driving the
Germans from the south bank of the
the western hattle line, brought the Aiane-Aire canal and reaching the
(Continued on page 2J.
(Continued on page 2.)
"V
GERMAN REPLY REJECTED
Lake, Minn., 102
at Duluth with oth-
Fifteen thousand
octors, nurses and state
,y though the
the work of
situation
rescuers.
curve with their cars, each adding of Duluth. These drove directly eastjed from the invaders Saturday and
to the wreckage. Fire had swept the toward the cities of Duluth and_Sup- yesterday.
pile and many burned bodies were
removed,
erior, Wis., both of which were singed, j' xhe big west front salient extend
Other fires originating to the north, |„g from the region of Oambral to
comman-1 encircled the head of lake Superior.' Verdun is thus orumbllng for Its en-
deered every available automobile gome towns of the path of the flames length and the Germane are stag
were saved by surrounding Bwampa. gering back toward the hnpassable
Others were wiped out and are mere I Ardennes mountalna.
blackened ruins today. I |n the north there still remains the
Residents of these cities harried gowned valenclennea line.
east for refuge. Some were reported
fugees from the water and hurried
them to Duluth where other hundreds
were cared for.
Adjt. Gen. W. P. R-hlnow ordered
300 caskets shipped to the fire swept
district, but the number of deaths was
only a guess.
Relief trains today crept through
LAST HI
[United Pre#« Leased Wttre Servlca.]
LONDON Oct. 14*—'The l«st great
Oorman itronghold In Frewe Is in
the hands of the allies.
The St. Gobain maeelf, wMch form
ed the cornerstone of the enemy's de
fensive system—the most powerful
the world has ever known, waa wrest-
ayu
overtaken. in automobiles. Trains ||ed blow*, tout Its hasty construction
jammed to capacity ran terrifying, earwrt have rendered It oomparable
racjea with .the nrea leaping through
W|th
adjoining tlmberlanda. fwaa four years In building.
At Moose LaAf. Mdnn.. a score stood
neck deep In the lake over night fight-1
rushed to the district, dragged the re-
Among Minnesota towns reported are within eighteen milea of
orjwticallv wined out are Cloquet. To the eastward of Laon the Frencn
Brookston, Brevator, Corona, Odenah, and Americans teve Pr^caJl* j^e
1</text>
    </result>


	<result>
		<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030431/1918-10-15/ed-1/?sp=4&q=Cloquet+Fire&st=text&r=-0.174,-0.067,1.348,1.348,0</id>
		<rel>1</rel>
		<text>21 TOWS, THOUSAND
LIVES, FIRE'S TOLL
Vast Quantities of Timber and
Crops Lost in Minnesota
Disaster.
THOUSANDS HOMELESS
Searchers Find Bodies of 300
in the Moose Lake Sec
tion Alone.
Dcirrn, Minn., Oct 14. Twenty-one
towns were destroyed, probably 1,000
Uvea lost and vast quantities of timber
and crops swept away by the forest
Area in northeastern Minnesota Saturday
and Sunday. The towns totally or partly
destroyed are Coquet, Moose Lake,
Kettle River, Lawler, Adolph, Mungsr,
Five porners, Harney, Grand Lake,
Maple Grove. Twlr, Qarnum, Mathews,
Atkinson, French River. Clifton, Carle
ton, Brookaton, Brsvator, Pika Lake and
Pins HllL
The monetary loss at Cloqust, accord
ing; to the estimate of business men of
that city, was f 12,000.000.
Gov, Bumqulst and Adj. -Gen. Rhlnow
arrived here to-nlfht and Immediately
went Into conference with W. A. Mc
Jonagle. chairman of the Northern Dis
trict of Red Cross, and A. C. Weiss, Du
ll th. member of the Public Safety Com
mission, to consider means of carlnc tor
refugees.
Moose Lakx, Mini... Oct. li. Men
and women of the Moose Lake district
of Minnesota, driven by fir from their I
homes, penniless, many of them wearing
clothing furnished by charitable relief
workers, to-night took up the search for
their dead.
Barred by the military authorities
from leaving the city, they wandered
between long lines of bodies In the Im
provised morgues here, searching for
loved ones who have not been heard
from since the forest fires laid waste
this section of Minnesota and a portion
of northern Wisconsin four days ago.
Motor, trucks arriving at frequent In
tervals brought in more and more bodies
and the vigil of the watchers continued
throughout the night.
Searcher Are Tireless.
During the last twenty-four hours
the bodies of 300 victims have been
found In the charred no man's land,
which before the fire formed the shores
of Moose Lake and Kettle River. The
majority of the bodies, some of which
were taken to Duluth, were so badly
charred that Identification will be dif
ficult. Searchers have been on duty for
ten hours, but there has been as yet no
slackening of ths pace or shortening of
Intervals at which the bodies are
brought In.
AdjL-Cfon. Rhlnow to-night estimated
that the number of dead In the Moos'
Lake and Kettle River regions alone
might reach 500. These, with the other
dead from adjoining regions, will. It Is
believed, swell the list near to the 1,000
mark.
Improvised hospitals here and the per
manent Institutions at Duluth are car
Ins; for thousands of more or less In
jured refugees, many of whom are In
a critical condition.</text>
    </result>

	<result>
		<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86063381/1918-10-25/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Cloquet+Fire&st=text&r=-0.012,0.088,0.934,1.216,0</id>
		<rel>0</rel>
		<text>None</text>
    </result>

	<result>
		<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn78000395/1918-11-02/ed-1/?sp=4&q=Cloquet+Fire&st=text&r=-0.227,-0.073,1.454,1.454,0</id>
		<rel>1</rel>
		<text>BURNQUIST RESPONSIBLE.
The Minnesota. Union Advocate of
St. Paul holds Governor Burnquist
responsible for the forest fire which
recently laid to waste such a great
area fn Northeastern Minnesota. It
holds that if the governor had been
vigilant before the, fire and heeded
importunate and inSJstenf* vfArnings
of the imminent danger from forest
fires in the region of Moose Lake
filed with him and the safety com­
mission by Forest Ranger Swedberg,
the awful calamity would not have
befallen the people of. this .territory.
Ten days before the calamity at
Moose Lake, Mr. Swedberg wrote
from that town to the capitol in St.
Paul:
"I consider it now necessary to ask
the Minnesota commission of public
safety to stop the Soo from running
its small standard engines during the
balance of the fire season.
"If the present weather continues
the fire question will soon be beyond
all control, so far as we are con­
cerned, unless this railroad can be
muzzled.
"In a few days there will be just
one continuous fire through this dis­
trict along the Soo.</text>
    </result>


	<result>
		<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn89081022/1918-11-20/ed-1/?sp=5&q=Cloquet+Fire&st=text&r=0.019,0.122,0.694,0.904,0</id>
		<rel>1</rel>
		<text>BURNED TOWNS
BEING REBUILT
Many Temporary Structures Now
In Use—Relief Funds Con
tinue to Arrive.
Cloquet, the largest town destroyed
in The big fire of October 12th, Is
to be rebuilt bigger and better than
ever, according to word received here
from business and commercial inter
ests of that city. Already there are
many business firms that have re
turned to the town, and have put up
temporary quarters in which to carry
on their business. The families of
the men of Cloquet are returning as
fast as temporary shacks are erected
to house them from the elements. By
this time next year there will be
comfortable homes in place of the
shacks, but just now they stand for
"home", and for courage and grit to
make the best of a desperate situa
tion Other towns are also being
rebuilt, and every assistance possi
ble is being given to the farmers and
settlers of that region to make it
possible for them to stay on their
land.
Not only the people of Northern
Minnesota and Wisconsin, but people
from all over the country sent in
money to aid the sufferers. Money
reached headquarters from points as
far apart as Maine and Washington,
and from Canada to the Gulf. This
money is being wisely expended,
those who have the work of re-con
struction in hand realizing that
theirs is a work of many months,
and that only the immediate needs
of the people can be met at this time.
The, State Tax commission sent
word to the county auditors of the
various counties where the fires had
caused serious loss that the penalty
and interest would be abated on the
current taxes of those settlers who
lost heavily in the fire. This will
give them till the latter part of De
cember in which to pay the last half
of the current taxes.
The Itasca County Mutual Fire
Insurance company suffered some
losses in the fire, but not enough to
cripple it in any way. A small as
sessment will take care of all losses
incurred. The case is diflerent with
the Carlton county farmers company.
Their losses will reach a huge sum,
and assessments will not care for the
losses. It is understood that there is
a movement on foot in the state de
partment of insurance to take care
of the mutual companies that were
hard hit till they can get a fresh
start
Stories of the big fire are still be
ing told by survivors. One instance
of the terrific wind is seen in the
story told by relable witnesses that
on Sunday morning after the fire
paper and stationery of the North
ern Lumber company was picked up
at Black River Falls, Wis., a distance
of about thirty miles.</text>
    </result>


	<result>
		<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn92066929/1927-05-11/ed-1/?sp=5&q=cloquet+fires</id>
		<rel>1</rel>
		<text>The United States Forest Ser
vice places the average annual num
ber of forest fires in the United
States during the past 10 years at
51,000. The average area swept
by fires each year stands at 15,-
000,000 acres. The annual damage
runs up to $20,000,000, not taking
into account the damage to young
growth, watersheds and recreational
facilities, which can hardly be esti
mated.
It is believed that much of the
prairie country and perhaps some
of the plains of the United States
and Canada were converted to their j
treeless state by forest fires which
swept over them repeatedly in by
gone ages. If the fires occur fre
quently, the young growth, the
seeds and the fertile top soil itself
are destroyed.
The forest fire risk greatly in
creases with civilized settlement.
Ninety percent of the forest fires
today are man-caused. Hunters,
campers and tourists are often care
less with their camp fires, their
matches and tobacco; settlers who
set fires to clear land or to dis
pose of brush frequently allow them
to get out of hand; activities of
mining, lumbering and railroads
are often causes of fire.
Under favoring wind and humid
ity conditions, forest fires frequent
ly attain an enormous speed of ad
vance; tue front often leaps hun
dreds of feet forward, and burning;
I brands and sparks may establish j
branch fires miles ahead of the
main conflagration. Populous com
munities in the paths of such fires!
are sometime" wiped out in a few
minutes wUh great loss of life and
property. In the Hinckley and
Cloquet fires in Minnesota in 1894
and 1918, many hundreds of lives
were lost; in the Peshtigo, Wis.,
fire of 1875, 1,500 persons were
killed. It is probable that in the
last 125 years more timber in the
United States has been destroyed
by fires than has been used in all
the wood industries.</text>
    </result>


	<result>
		<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042414/1920-09-16/ed-1/?sp=1&q=cloquet+fires&st=text&r=-0.264,-0.076,1.528,1.528,0</id>
		<rel>1</rel>
		<text>In Decision Regarding
Famous Cloquet Fire
Duluth, Minn., Sept. 16.—The
judges of district court, sitting en
banc today, handed down a decision
!n favor of the plaintiffs in the fa
mous Cloquet fire cases against Unit
ed States Railroad Director W. D.
Hinee as wartime manager of the
Great Northern railroad. The deci
sion gives damages to 278 plaintiffs
and involves in round numbers $3,
000,000 resulting from the forest
fires of October 12, 1918. The deci
sion is looked upon as of still greater
importance because it fixes the lia
bility and origin of the fires in the
Cloquet district and will have a direct
bearing'on other suits which will in
volve about $10,000,000.
In the decision handed down today
the judges of district court say in
their memorandum that they experi
enced no difficulty in placing the ori
gin of the fire at mile post 62 on the
Great Northern road and tracing it in
a -crescent shaped area through sec
tions four and five in township 49-17.
The fixing of the origin at the fire
is regarded as the most Important
point, for it will be the basis for al
most all other suits growing out of
the famous fires which swept the
country surrounding Duluth on the
date mentioned, causing immense fin
ancial loss a°nd great sacrifice of life.
The decision has been looked for for
some time.
The railroad company is not direct
ly'' affected, for- the government as
sumed all liabilities during its han
dling.iof the road and the cost of- the
fires attributed'.the railroad's" fault
fcriU come out of the federal govern
ment's coffers.</text>
    </result>

	<result>
		<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88076741/1921-07-29/ed-1/?sp=6&q=cloquet+fires&r=0.103%2C0.336%2C0.727%2C0.474%2C0&st=text</id>
		<rel>1</rel>
		<text>According to the findings the fire
was .started at Mile Post 62, a distance
13 miles from Cloquet, and then swept
into the city. The claim of the rail
road company was that other fires or
iginating south and east of Cloquet
caused the losses. The court, however
disagreed, denied the petition for
amended findings or a new trial.
THOMSON SHORT $1,187,000
Property Turned Over By Defaulting
Comptroller Worth $1,000,000.
Chicago—Following an audit of the
books of the George A. Hormal com
pany of Austin, Minn., officers of the
company announced that the total
shortage of R. j. Thomson, former
company comptroller, was $1,187,000.
Thomson's property turned over con
sists of various stocks and bonds,
notes, mortgages and city real estate,
well as two farms in Minnesota and
one in Iowa, with all improvements
thereon, including a pure bred herd
of Holstein cows. George A. Hormel
said that it is impossible to state the
realizable value of this acquired prop
erty, but that its actual cost to Thom
son was in excess of $1,000,000.
PEARY'S SHIP TO THE RESCUE
North Pole Craft Will Tow, Amund
son's Boat Into Port.
Seattle, Wash.—The steamer Roose
velt, on which Admira) Robert Peary
penetrated the Arctic in his success
ful expedition to the North Pole, has
been chartered to go into Bering strait
to the relief of Captain Roald Amund
sen's disabled exploring ship Maud,
the captain announced.
The Roosevelt will tow the Maud to
Seattle,</text>
    </result>

	<result>
		<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88076433/1921-07-28/ed-1/?sp=2&q=cloquet+fires&st=text&r=-0.294,-0.079,1.589,1.589,0</id>
		<rel>1</rel>
		<text>U. S. IS HELD LIABLE
Court Blames Railroacf for Los
ses in Cloquet Fire.
1,000 Damage Cases Aggregating Be
tween $12,000,000 and $15,000,000
Involved.
ii-
St. Paul—The United States"railroad
administration is liable for damages
resulting from the Cloquet fire of 1918,
laid to the Great Northern railroad at
that time operated by the federal gov
ernment, the Minnesota state supreme
court decided.
Total liabilities for 278 cases which
have been reviewed will reach ap
proximately $2,000,000, whereas the
grand total of liability for the entire
group of approximately. 1,000 cases
will reach an amount aggregating be
tween $12,000,000 and $15,000,000.
The case originally was brought be
fore the St. Louis county district court
in the case ot Phillip Hall- against
James C. Davis, an.agent of the Presi
dent under the transportation act.
The St, Louis, court held that gov
ernment railroad administration liable.
The director general moved for
amended findings on a new trial and
the motion was, denied by the St. Louis
county authorities. The federal au
thorities then appealed from this to
the state supreme court, and the' su
^reme court in its decision denied the
appeal.
The finding of the Duluth court was
that the defendant was responsible for
the destruction of property in this fire
of October 12, 1918. In the order
signed by Judge W. A. Cant of Du
luth, Philip Hall, claimant in this par
ticular case, is entitled to $7,400 dam
ages.
According to the findings the fire
was started at Mile Post 62, a distance
13 miles from Cloquet, and then swept
into the city. The claim of the rail
road company was that other fires or
iginating south and east of Cioquet
caused the losses. The court, however
disagreed, denied the petition for,
amended findings or a new trial.</text>
    </result>

	<result>
		<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88076639/1921-12-01/ed-1/?sp=2&q=cloquet+fires&st=text&r=-0.274,-0.077,1.548,1.548,0</id>
		<rel>1</rel>
		<text>First Payments In Cloquet Fire cases
Expected to be Made
by Nov. 30th.
Duluth—First payments in a $5,
000,000 settlement of the, Cloquet fire
cases, resulting from-iiie forest fires
which swept northeastern Minnesota,
Oct. 13,1918, are expected to be made
by Nov. 30, as the result Jf a final
agreement reached recently between
the settlers and townspeople who suf
fered in the fires and the United
States railroad administration.
The procedure of turning over to
the fire victims their, shares ot the
settlement was held up for six weeks
by three sufferers who refused to com
promise with the administration be
cause they had obtained judgments in
district court previous to the signing
of the agreement.</text>
    </result>
     
	</results>
  </topic>

  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-great-blizzard-1888</id>
    <results>

      <result>
		<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1888-03-13/ed-1/?sp=1&q=blizzard+cold+Ic+ic+Ice+ice+snow&st=text&r=-0.295,-0.079,1.589,1.589,0</id>
		<rel>1</rel>
		<text>willing shove; the high walls at the side con?
ni.uted t.. this advantage. The result was thal
In. snow- piled Into the open cut find tilled it up
O thc level of the walls on either sid".
President IJ, pew itnd Super ut1 ndent Toueey
nada various SffCCtS through the day to br. air
brough thc snow covering the tracks between
he Bunion and the tunnel. Hut. lt was no use.
-Trst one engine vvas sent Steaming proudly north.
[he Missen] met it ?qaars t.) the cow-oateher
vith u solid front of snow. The engine did not
OOg butt at the blizzard in this form, but yielded
uni returned to the station.
Mr. Depew thought that the blissard must be
i trifle toucher limn nu after-dinner speech, ko
wo engines, coupled together, sailed proudly
Hirth. Their combined front un.l headway om!
he blizzard. Their combined tall cann! bach
..iwein their combined legs, so to speak. Mr.
Depew loolred solemn, nnd seemed to think that
ie had run sgainst something heavier than a
mom, and so throe eo_ine- went gavly tn the
lorth, their Strength united, tli. ir steam In full
'lav. 'I hey, too, met tbs blizzard disguised as
i nannies*; snow-bank. Then' the engines na?
nnied together. They b-d bucked'' against
lie blizzard and thc blizzard had won.
inn: K m'.\_ii!.i> iiaiivns disco*, ii ron.
Ic calling the st,.ry of the drops that wear
he rook, thc Grand Central powers hired them
np) Italians to begin an onslaught on tho biiz
ntrd. To break them in gently und givo them a
jnid taste ol tho storm, I. si tlie memory of sunny
Italy should ni1 lt their ardor, tiny were 8<'tit to
work in th.* yard. After an boura steady work,
ihe 3> ii, for..ii.ii of Leonidas, "kicked" sgainst
iho blizzard aud iusiblcd ou returning to their
nao caroni.
'lins event wm discouraging. Mr. Depew and
Mr. Toueey conferred. They bil on a pian. Mr.
Dcpew recalled the nntui*.-, tendency and ellet
>f good dinners, and h.- felt mrs that something
if this kind Would fetoh 'cm." So oin) moro
Italians were engaged later In rh day, nnd a g.I
tupper vvas the ti:sr hard work (hat they were
['nilli on to Walde through. They sueeeded in this
iital then tackled the blizzard, but us thc monster
held ihe whip hand and us d it vigorously, doubt
rt i d on the Grand Central power us tu whether
the Ital rt tis would weather the night.
rORTT TRAINS BTTJCff BELOW/ ITajt.DL-.Wir.
All hope of doing anything to remove ths snow
fr,.in tl.,* tunnel was abandoned until tho wind
should abate its vehemence. Superintendent
louey .said late itl th" dav that MOM forty trains
srers snow bound between One humircd-und-teiith
st. and Woodlawn Junction on thc Harlem Hoad,
mid Spuyten Dujrvll on the Central. H.* at least
kll.'W', UC sn;.I, ti,ill ta.ll nuill'ler of traills WON
due, and that s,, fur us h.; could Judge th,- blizzard
had captur d the trains within a distance of at
least thirty miles. Hie trouble lay between this
city end Vonki is. 'ino Springfield sleeping oar
train on th- New-Haven and dartford line wus
tin- h; at train to come in. and that arrived bet .'.ecu
ll it. tn. and noon. Note train had gone out lroai
tho Grand Central station during th.- day.
l.HTi.!. Si.n.inv -BOYS FKEK-XILL,
At 7 u. m. Mr, lou,, y had reoelved word fron
r.eksk'Ti that there was hardly any snow there.
At thal point and else*W_em beyond the railroad
ohio ia la hud had no inca that tum city was in
thc embraoe of thc blizzard, lt wa. no one's
fault, he thought, that trains wire sent forth
on theil' usual runs to this mty and thus forced
to bc piled up within a sh,ut distance ol lim etty
lo o.i.se no dispel ode tue eily had uny
idea to thu Hains wcio to bc surprised with
this kimi ol ;i reception. 'Joe blizzard bad corns
unannounced and b-d swooped down on the rail
inn.is hereabouts without warning. The wires
went down and noan, ali communication with
the outside world wus bu,a ..it beyond "-.payton
1 *uy v il.
A telegram vvas "received from Buffalo before
noon thai lue sun was si'itiiii. In (hat city, and
i h.< water from th.- melting snow running in
tin- stree ta Even th.- lung distance telephone
I,, .Mi.any gave out, ami no word could ht* got
o\,-I' it. 'Til.- Stamford local gol us tar as One
liuiuIre*l-icid tent ii sr and two passengers walked
down to the si anon Iq bones to take tao elevated
road. Their hopes wt te flashed,
l ROW LS AT ?lill-. ORAN 1) (.?'?.NTH. VI. STATli'.N.
People hoping lo depart by rail from ths Grand
Central station kept arriving ut that point from
farlous paru of tlio olty ali day. They heard
tho news, expressed themselves in warm terras
about the blizzard i peclally eitel having paul
from $iu so a-*:", for a cab?and then, then- cob
having slready departed, they got back to their
hons, i us best they could.</text>
      </result>
    
      <result>
		<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026844/1888-03-13/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Blizzard+blizzards</id>
		<rel>1</rel>
		<text>Unprecedented Blizzard Rages
Throughout the East, "v'
hi
PRACTICALLY STOPS BUSINESS i"
III Sew York City uml Cutu Off* Telegraphic
Communication with the
lOiiMtci'ii Ci ti cm Traffic 1h
almost Knfirciy SuNpeiulcd. ,S]
In
New Youk, March 12.?The hardest
unnu> uturf nf fim vonr bv far !h rairinit ?t<
in New York City. It began early this tji
morning and iji,8 o'clock was a foot or tj,(
over on the ground. A high wind
caused drifts Which, in the upper part
of the city, were three and four feet ac
high. Traffic was almost suspended. th
Thousands of passengers were blocked
on the elevated roads. The people who
left uptown by the elevated roods were 11
unable to get further than Eighth street Sp
by the road. Many of the more venturesome
descended to the street by dc
1 ladder and walked the rest of the way th
down town. People in suburban towns c<
fouud it almost impossible to reach the to
city. Tj
At 7:10 this morning, two trains on _
the Thirut Seventy-sixth street station. One ni
train was at the station unloading and ca
taking on passengers, with which it was Pr
Already over-crowded. Owing to the
show on the tniek, the train was unable "l
to start. After it had been standing
about twenty minutCH, to the horror of
all, a train came rushing down the in- ,H
cline from Seventy-fourth street and c?
dashed into the rear car. The scene that Wl
followed was indescribable. The engine
reared up on the end of the last car and 11
steuin escaped in great volumes, but for-
tunatcly rushed upwards, thus saving
the hemmcd-in crowd of the forward
train as well as those on the end of the
olatforin. The engineer of the rear train "J
killed and a number of passengers were
injured. fi1'
An Albany dispatch says: The snow
storm in this vicinity is the severest of
tho season. Horsecars ure-block and
trains arc hours behind. If the storm
continues, of which there is every prospect,
there will be u general train block- ac
adc before night. of
A dispatch from Troy says: About ?.i
fifteen inches of snow lias fallen here g,
and still falling; seventeen inches re- j
ported at Saratoga. The Flitchburg train ju]
came in about an hour late; lienmngtou
and Rutland train is stalled in the drifts
near Iloosic Junction. A train from the jn,
north arrived about thirty-live minutes
late. The morning mail on the Hudson H(?
river track from New York was two nr
hours late. Kailroad men believe that cj,
they have not seen the worst of the co
storm, however, and predict a very fieri-
ous time if the wind increases. tn
Business is virtually at a stand-still.
Down-town houses are" almost deserted.
Only two trains arrived with the mails
this morning aud work at the postoflice i
was paralyzed. The carriers made two pa
trips, butin many cases had to bring the j,.
mail back, owing* to business oflices being
closed. Postmaster Harrison said he St<
had not seen such a blockade for a num- en
lx?r of years. All the telegraph and sei
telephone wires in the city arc in bad hi)
wonting order. Hundreds* of wires are he
down, having been broken by the mass
of ice and snow. The ferry-boats be-
tween Now York and Brooklyn and ,H
New Jersey are running once in an hour
or less. th</text>
      </result>

      <result>
		<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83032300/1888-03-13/ed-1/?sp=1&q=BLIZZARD+blizzard+cold+Ice+snow+SNOW+Snow+snowed+SNOWED&st=text&r=0.094,0.135,0.717,0.717,0</id>
		<rel>1</rel>
		<text>A FURIOUS BLIZZARD.
8Krs.lt 41, JNCBKS OF SHOW CAUSE KX
IKNglVE RlIt,WlT DBTBNnOIf,
Trains Bald Firmly Iy III Baew Drift
and Stag Beat "Impassable Tels
araphle uommanleatlea Oreatry
Impaired Kttrjbaaj SatTerlag.
During the past thirty-six been Lan
caster baa bad an experience that liaa
seldom been equalled In Its history. In
deed the town baa been almost abnt out
from tbe world and all this trouble la owing
te tbe aovera mew aterm of Sunday night,
and tbe high wlnda that followed, canting
unusually large drifts. Daring the whole
of Monday and last night, net enetraln
reached Lancaater from Philadelphia or any
ether point (tat of tbta city en tbe Penn
ey I van la railroad, and the people have al al
mejt forgotten what a Philadelphia news
paper leeks like, Tbe trouble lsnotoon lsnetoon lsnoteon
11 aed te tbe railroad alone. The telegraph
companies are also sufferer. The wires of
the Weatern Union and Biltlmere
Ohie companies were down and it wastm wastm
pessible te get any message te Philadelphia
lat night Luge piles of measagea that
bad come from the West were alaeked In
the Western Union office, but they could
net ba handled The United Lines s'to s'te
ceeded In getting off a tew message. The
Pennsylvania railroad company's wires
were In a terribly demoralized condition,
and it was next te Impossible te send mes mes
sages te Philadelphia directly from this
city en this account little could be learned
at the tower In tbe station.
Men who have bean emp'.oyel en th9
Pennsylvania railroad for many years say
that they have never known the company
te have as mnea trenble as this snow has
caused. The dllUeulty at Downlngtewn
ejn be traced te the wreck of Sanday
night This caused a blockade and gave
the snow a chinos te Interfere with the
trains. During yesterday the only trains
that were successfully run were these be
tween Lancaster and Columbia. Others
were all la'e and most of them
were annulled entirely. The Pennsylvania
station presented a lively appsaranee all
day Monday and In the night It was lllled
with people who were anxious te get te
their homes. Most of these came from
towns west of Lancaster, as none bad been
able te reaeh here from tbe east, during tbe
day. The large waiting room of the Pennsyl
vania read was open ail night, and many
persons slept en the benebes, thus keeping
out or the oeld. The restaurants and hotels
In the neighborhood did a thriving trade.
Seme of tbe strangers, wbe became tired
waiting for tbe train, put In the time by get
ting very big leida of rum en beard, wbleh
seemed te keep them warm and In geed
humor.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
		<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058130/1888-03-13/ed-1/?sp=1&q=BLIZZARD+blizzard+cold+ice+ices+IceS+Snow+snow&st=text&r=-0.31,-0.081,1.62,1.62,0</id>
		<rel>1</rel>
		<text>EASTERN BLIZZARD
An Unprecedented Storm of
Wind and Snow
TRAFFIC IMPEDED ALL OVER
Casualties In the BIz Cltio The Tele
graph DemoralizedSad Havoc
EverywhereEtc
The Storm
NEW YORK March 12The storm is
general in New York State Connecticut
and points south From all surround
ing countries come reports of the se
verest snow and windstorm in years
There was a similar accident to that on
Third Avenue on the Brooklyn elevated
road this morning but at
tended by no casualties Business is
virtually at a standstill Down town
houses are almost deserted Only two
trainb arrived with mails this morning
and the work of the postoffice is
partially suspended A hundred tel
graph wires are down Ferry boats
between New York Brooklyn and New
Jersey are running once an hour or
less The wind attained a velocity of
sixtyfour miles an hour
PouoHKEEPsiK N Y March 12
About 8 this morning in a blinding
snowstorm an express train bound
south on the New York Central ran
into another express at Dobbs Ferry
demolishing several cars Jour persons
were badly injured Both tracks are
obstructed
NKW HAVEN Conn March 12The
storm in this vicinity is very bad At
11 oclock no trains had arrived from
New York
TROY March 12The storm in wes
tern New York is about fifteen inches
deep and is still falling Traffic is
greatly impeded
NEW YORK March 127 p mThe
storm is increasing It is absolutely
unprecedented All business has been
paralyzed At the Stock Exchange less
than 15000 shares were sold the smal
lest on record The produce markets
are all nominal The steamers City of
Berlin and La Champagne have arrived
out The weather stopped the courts
Every street car in New York and the
Brooklyn and Jersey City elevated
trains are stopped Brooklyn bridge
and the ferries are almost abandoned
Downtown hotels are crammed with
suburbanites The elevated roads run
3000 trains daily usually They never
before stopped Westerners declare
that Dakota never furnished New
York blizzard of today Of the
forty mails due between 4 and noon
only two arrived by 2 this afternoon
The news from Europe where also
tremendous gales and snow storms arc
occurring is unimportant and un
interesting mainly relating to the ob
sequies of the late Emperor
9oclock this evening there was
no abatement in the storm Frozen
ears and feet were never so numerous
The drug stores were filled with
patients all day and evening A</text>
      </result>
      
	  <result>
		<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030272/1888-03-13/ed-1/?sp=1&q=blizzard+Blizzard+BLIZZARD+blizzards+cold+ice+Ice+Snow+snow+SNOWED+snowing</id>
		<rel>1</rel>
		<text>In English Price One Cent
VOL LYNO n 105 NEW YORK TUESDAY MARCH 1 1888 PRICE TWO CENTS 1
BLIZZARD WAS KING
The Metropolis Helpless
Under Snow
S HARDLY WHEEL TURNS
Business Knockel Flat as f
b a Panic
PLAYS TRIALS FUNERALS
ALL POSTPONED
Fifty Train Loads of Passengers
Black on the Main Lines
WHERE THEY ARE HEAVEN KNOWS
A fonder Change in Onr Ways of
Urine and Maying Sprung on
Us in a Night
ELECTRIC LIGHTS OUT
MIGHTY LITTLE NEWS GOT INTO
TOWN OR GOT OUT OF IT
GOING TO LET UP NOW
I
The Elevated Roads After a Days I
Paralysis Get a laU Hold
Again on Travel
Agin rave
It was u i New York had been a burning
Midi upon which nature bad clapped a mut
ter leaTinr nothing ot the citys activity but 0
strui allng ember
At little after 18 oclock on Sunday nl bt or
Monday monitor the lover rain that had been
pelting doW aoe the moment ot the opening
I tho church doors sudd nly changed t a
ileet etorm that plated the sidewalks with Ico
Then bgu the great ittorm that Is 1 to become
r0 years l household word a symbol ol the
worst of weathers and the limit ot natures
possibilities under normal conditions
At f quarter past 8 oclock when the ex
tremely modified sunlight forced Its way to
earth the Boon In tb two great cities that the
bridge unites was remarkable beyond any win
ter sight remembered bJ the people The
streets were blocked with snowdrifts The car
tricks went hid bore cars were not in the
range ot possibilities a wind of wild velocity
bowled between the rows ot houses the nlr
was burdened with soft wet clinging enow
only bore and there was a wagon to be aeon
only here and there a feebly moving man
The wind howled whittled banged roared
and moaned aa it rushed alone It fell upon
the house aides In fearful Busts I strained
great plate glass windows rocked the frame
houses pressed against doors so that It was
almost dangerous t open thorn I was a visi
ble substantial wind so freighted was It wlt
enow I camo In wulrla It descended In lay
ers I shot along In lat blocks It rose and
jell and corkscrewed and zigzagged and played
merry bavoo with everything It could swing or
bat r or banK or carry away
It was Monday morning when a day of rest I
from shopping hud depleted the larders In
every house and yet there wore no milk carts
no butcher wagons no basketladen grocer
boys no bakers carrier In great districts no
attempt was made to delIver the morning
papers The cities wore paralyzed
Few of th women who work for their living
could get to their wont places Nover perhaps
In the history of petMcoats was the Imbecil
ity o their designer better Illustrated To
ot here I bad to take my Bklrts up and
clamber through tim snowdrifts said awash
woman when she caine to tho house ot the reporter
oJan</text>
      </result>

      <result>
		<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030272/1888-03-15/ed-1/?sp=1&q=blizzard+Blizzard+cold+Ice+ice+SNOW+snow+Snow+snowed</id>
		<rel>1</rel>
		<text>WE ARE ON TOP NOV
The Town Has Got the
Blizzard Down
NO LONGER ISOLATED
I
Through Trains Move Cars More
Coal CarLs Move
WE WANT MORE MILK
Wo Wont a Good Deal More of
Telegraph Facilities
DIGGING OUT AND THAWING OUT
Bonfires i the Snow Drifts Litera I
ture on the Snow Drifts
WAEM AOT FAIR TODAY
No Sudden Thaw Likely No Rubber
Boots but No 11s
From the gray and dubious dawn t the
golden and glorious sunset things were mov
Inc in New York yesterday Some things were
moving yet earlier and later They wero shov
els These useful Implements were tbe most
restlessly active articles in aU the restlessness
of a town that la 1 tired of resting They were
worked by thousands of Italians in squads
that had enlisted undor the banners of Com
missioner Coleman or of the street railroad
folks who were mining for the burled iron of
their tracks through depths of snow packed to
the sold consistency of Ice These squads were
working with tho help of pickax wielders
and were reinforced and supported In many I
Instances by a force of carts to remove the dis I
integrated mass In other places the pick and
I shovel brigades built high and solid ramparts
alongside the tracks of the mottled and mar
bled blocks they raised from the pavement or
cut chalk white channels through drifts and
pied them to greater heights on either side
The number and size of these gangs of
shovellers suggested the thought that the
city was becoming Latinized to an extent un
dreamed of But a study of them would not
bear out this conclusion Ameng them wore
welldmswxl and comfortable looking men
kidgloved day laborers as I wero The stag
nation of business the ordinary channels is
te probable explanation of this Another
vast though scattered army of shovel bran
dlshers were those who in pursuit of contract
work scorned the 11 and 2 a day toll of the
gong laborers and wanted S5 for digging out a
west side or north side house front Yet a trip
up the Bowery disclosed the usual number of
loungers about the cheap lodging houses
Thesearo the chronlo seekers after work BO
thoroughly used to looking for It that they
have no time t do it when they find It
Btlll other hundreds of the evermoving
hovels were agitated by children and women I
Tb former mao up by activity for lack of
strength Cut the latter mad a mess of it In
their attacks on the huge snow piles Their
training and their weapons were against
them There were a groat many of them to be
seen up town down town and all over town
but their little Ore shovels and the kitchen
okr for picks wore not very effectual An
other trouble was their different notion of
work A man would attack a drift with tho
simple purpose of dislodging It No matter
though snow remained under his feet I the big
pie was over the gutter instead of on the side
walk lie was content But woman though
cleaning a spot only big enough to sere as a
resting place for her dainty feet must have
that spot broom clean and dry or feel as
though she had Buffered defeat
JJONPIBES TO HELP THE THAW
Tho third day of the great blockade began
with discouraging symptoms of another snow
dlscouralng
fall and mUll 2 oclock In the afternoon there
wan aBtrngellng deposit of big wet flukes that
suggested the lust and by no means the least
dlslresslnl stage tho thaw I thawed just
enough to help things on a little The great
drifts in tho streets are bad enough but noth
tog could bo worse than a sudden transforma
tion of the snow to slush and water Itoads
full of snow may bo rendered passable by pa
tent work but against slush feet deep there
i no remedy The threatening rain did not
come though and at 3 oclock the sun peered
through the clouds as I to tell tie Signal
Service Department that the elements I would
do what they could to justify Its prediction of
far and Mfghtly warmer weather
An original genius on Vesey street conceived
the plan of building a lire on the big drifts be
fore his Btoro und all over the lower part of
the city his example was quickly followed The
air was full of brown smoke and the appetiz
ing odor of bonllres The method was unique
I unllue
and Interesting A hole excavated in the
drift of about tho capacity of a cubic yard
From tbe top of this to the top of the drift a I
funnel wa made to secure ventilation Then
trenches nere dug at the sides of the dilit to
conduct the water to the gutters The bole
was fled with barrels of shavings and paper
and empty packing boxes and tired Tho fuel
burnod right meriily and the Interior tho
drifts were speedily toasted ut least they
looked toasted for tho cinders and smoke dis
colored the snow to n dark brown and as time
passed tbe drifts gradually milled away This
artificial thaw caused no rerlouu discomfort
to pedestrians and It greatly facilitated tho
reception and delivery of goods at the many
stores where it was employed</text>
      </result>

      <result>
		<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn91068402/1888-03-22/ed-1/?sp=1&q=BLIZZARD+blizzard+Blizzard+Blizzards+cold+ICE+ice+ices+Snow+snow+snowed&st=text&r=0.126,0.251,0.227,0.295,0</id>
		<rel>1</rel>
		<text>THE GREAT STORM.
LOCKED IN THE ARMS OF THE
ICE KING.
The North Treated to a Blizzard of the
Genuine Western Style Great Suf
fering and Loss of Life Business
Paralyzed, &c, &c.
New Yorlc awoke yesterday after a
day and night of most wonderful ex.
periences and peeped timidly out of
the window to see if it had gone. It
had, but there remained a great deal
to remember it by. The principal and
most tangible token was snow. Snow
was every wheie and in greater quanti
ties than ever was known here. The
wind had heaped it up into great
mounds, as a giant would, and then as
an aitist would, it had taken little par.
tides and formed them into fantastic
sh&pes. The streets were filled with it,
and house fronts were plastered with it.
Then New York pulled itself to
gether and ruminated about how to
get rid of this memento. Desirable it
might be in some localities, but the
metropolis does not care for it. As a
result, towards nightfall little mounds
began to make their appearance in a
great many streets. These were not
the work of giants, but of ordinary hu
man beings, chiefly Italians. It was
the first step toward bringing the city
back to its normal condition.
With this end in view other agencies
got to work. Very early in the morn
ing steam began to puff from elevated
railroad engines, and trains began to
appear. They were not such big trains
as usual, nor did they travel so fast.
There was caution in their movements,
born of the experience of the day be
fore. But they availed to carry pas
sengers, and everybody was able to
go where they wanted to.
There were many signs to indicate
what devastation can be produced in
oDe day. One of these was the diffi
culty with which those prime and lore
most articles of necessity, food and
fuel, were procured. In a great many
instances the difficulty could not be
overcome and many poor people had
to rely on scanty stores. There was an
incipient famine in mat, milk and
coal.
Not one street car turned out for
traffic in the city yesterday. Such an
event has never happerfd before in the
memory of the oldest car driver or
conductor. By some means the com
panies have always before managed to
run a few cars during the worst storms,
but the bluxard on Monday paralyzed
them all.
The second day ol the great storm,
although less severe than the first, was
even more terrible through the prolon
gation of inconvenience, the gradual
diminution of necessary supplies and
revelations, of the damage the tempest
has done. Paris, encircled by the
German hosts, was scarcely more com
pletely isolated from the outtr world
than New York and its suburbs are .to
day. Within twelve miles of this city
7
there are trains full of teoDle imoris-
i r j j
oncd in the snow, cut off from food er
fuel and suffering what miseries we do
not know. We can only hope that
their tribulations may be light. We
cannot send aid to them, any more
than the roads on which they are
blocked can bring supplies to us.
Within the town well-known citizens
are found dead in snow drifts almost
at the threshold of their comfortable
homes, and to go from domicile to of
fice or workshop is still a task which
the majority dare not attempt. May
another day bring complete deliver
ance from this great calamity, the loss
by which to New York and the region
afflicted like the metropolis is not to
be measured by money, no matter to
how many millions we advaneed the
estimate.
BLIZZARD PRICES FOR COAL.
Blizzards come but seldom, nor lin
ger long. Should this one continue,
however, for any lengthened period,
more prayers will b said for the clerk
of the weather jjsan were ever before
offered up for the welfare of that in
dividual. While all New York is pray
ing a it never prayed before for the
Western visitor to take itself back to
its more congenial climate, there are
a large number of individuals wh
pray that he may remain. These last
are the coal dealers.
Despite the railroad strikes the price
cf black diamonds had not increased
to any great extent. When, however,
on Monday morning the coal dealer</text>
      </result>

      <result>
		<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042588/1888-03-23/ed-1/?sp=4&q=blizzard+blizzards+cold+coldness+ice+snow+Snow+snowed&st=text&r=-0.22,-0.072,1.44,1.44,0</id>
		<rel>1</rel>
		<text>THE STORY OF THE STORM.
The New York papers tell the story of
the stoma better thau the meagre reports
sent over the wires. The people of the
west who never saw or heard of such a
storm can hardly realize the terrors of
the storm of li$st week in old New Eng­
land. The following quotations from
eastern papers will be read with interest
by the TRIBUNE'S readers:
New oi Herald: All business was
abandoned, and the snow drifted in moun­
tains against miles and miles of closed
business houses. The elevated railways
ceased running, and all the horse car lines
were completely blocked up. Huge trees
In Twenty-third and other streets were
pulled up out o£ the ground and thrown in
all directions by the mighty wind which
increased in strength every moment. Men
and women were thrown about like straws,
and many had to be dug out of the vast
drifts. Wall street looked like an icy gulch
in Montana. Ferry boats were blown help­
lessly up ana down the North and East
rivers in the shrieking tempest, and no
vessel dared to enter the storm-smitten har­
bor. Trains on all the railways were
snowed in. The telegraph companies re­
fused to take messages. A horror of dark­
ness deepened over the crowded city, and
the terror-stricken population cowered at
the awful sound which came from the
throat of the whirlwind. Through the wild
clouds of snow that were driven along the
streets could be seen loaded waeons given
up by their drivers. At every turn could
be seen these deserted vehicles. Their
owners had fled for their lives, apparently
regardless of what became of the property.
Butchers' wagons, piled high with meat,
milk trucks crowded with cans, grocers'
wagons, coal carts, street cars were scat­
tered in the mountains of snow in all
directions. There were thousands upon
thousands of these abandoned wagons and
carts, some overturned, some lying across
the street, some half buried in the drifts.
Here and there they formed enormous
barricades, which caught the snow and
rolled it up in solid barriers.
With men and women dying in her ghost­
ly streets. New York saw day breaking
through the wild clouds yesterday (Wed
nesday, March 14th morning. Nature had
overwhelmed the metropolis, and citizens
were found dead in the mighty snow drifts.
White, frozen hands sticking up out of the
billowed and furrowed wasteS testified to
the unspeakable power that had desolated
the city. Had Jules Verue written such a
story a week ago New Yorkers would have
laughed and pronounced it a clever but im
possible romance. Yet here was the
stupendous reality. Within forty-eight
hours the city was converted into an Arc
tic wilderness, cut off from all railway and
telegraph communication. The white hur
ricane had strewn her busiest and gayest
thoroughfares with wreck and ruin. Courts
of justice were closed, and the vast
machinery of commerce was paralyzed.
Groans of mutilated humanity filled the air.
The wind blew at the rate of sixty miles
anliour.
As high as $50 was charged by cabmen
to transport travelers.
No milk was received for forty-eight
iH
hours in New York and as high as SI per
quart was paid, where it was wanted
the sick.
The electric light wires were down and
New York was left in darkness.
Over twenty-five funeral processions
were stalled, and in' some instances the
hearses and carriages were left in the
street and completely covered with snow.
Doubtless hundreds of sick people died
from the want of medical aid. It was al
most impossible for doctors to get along
the streets.
It is estimated over 5,000 babes depend­
ing on cow's milk had to go without for
two days.
Syracuse Courier: Snow Ten Feet Deep.
Rochester Herald: Winter's Death
Struggle.
Albany Express: Polaric Paralysis—A
Borean Blowout.
Albany Argus: Deep in Drifts—Several
States Buried Beneath Snowy Mantles.
Elizabeth Herald: The Snow Nine Feet
Deep Between This City And Newark.
Jersoy City Journal: An Old Time Bliz­
zard—The Oldest Inhabitant Can Brag No
More.
Boston Daily Advertiser: Bravo, Dakota!
Your blizzard experience this winter has
not frozen out your sense of humor. That
dispatch offering help toward food and
raiment for the sufferers of New York and
other seaboard cities during the present
blizzard week covers you with giory.
Brookly Standard-Union: Those who
had provisions on the snowed-in sides
were lucky, because neither butcher nor
baker nor groceryman made the usual
rounds for orders, and those who had not
and were unable to dig themselves out suf­
fered severely.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
		<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/2010270509/1952-12-11/ed-1/?sp=2&q=great+blizzard1888&r=0.56,0.46,0.471,0.307,0</id>
		<rel>0</rel>
		<text>None</text>
      </result>

      <result>
		<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/2010270509/1952-12-11/ed-1/?sp=2&q=great+blizzard1888&r=0.56,0.46,0.471,0.307,0</id>
		<rel>0</rel>
		<text>None</text>
      </result>

      <result>
		<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/2010270509/1952-12-11/ed-1/?sp=2&q=great+blizzard1888&r=0.56,0.46,0.471,0.307,0</id>
		<rel>0</rel>
		<text>None</text>
      </result>

      <result>
		<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/2010270509/1952-12-11/ed-1/?sp=2&q=great+blizzard1888&r=0.56,0.46,0.471,0.307,0</id>
		<rel>0</rel>
		<text>None</text>
      </result>

      <result>
		<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/2010270509/1952-12-11/ed-1/?sp=2&q=great+blizzard1888&r=0.56,0.46,0.471,0.307,0</id>
		<rel>0</rel>
		<text>None</text>
      </result>

    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>
