<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-alaska-gold-rush</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn99021999/1890-05-04/ed-1/?sp=5&q=Alaska+gold+rush</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>THE COLD FIELDS OF ALASKA
Statistics of the Mineral Woilth of the Ac
quisition of 1867.
AMERICA'S MOST PROFITABLE MINES
Grout Mountains ol' Mineral Wealth
A uniting Development The Need
of Go\eminent Aid in Mak
ing Explorations.
II. Kmtlty late United States Judge of
Mal a. In the Arena for Mttv.
Since the acquisition of Alaska in 1867
public attention In regard to it has boon
mainly directed to the salmon fisheries
in Its waters and to the seal rookeries in
Bohring sea. The value of the country
as a dependency has boon wholly deter
mined by the public from the rental
which the PrlbOlolT Islands yield to the
national treasury. Few references in the
intor\-oning period have boon made by
public journals and in the periodical
literature of the country to the gold-
yielding capabilities of Alaska or' to the
degree of development already reached.
The truth Is that hundreds of thousands
of intelligent Americans are profoundly
ignorant of the fact that some of the
largest and most profitable gold mining
ontorpribcs within the limits of the
United States are conducted in Alaska.
Gold in variable quantities and under
different conditions has been found in
three principal districts of Alaska the
Juneau and Douglass Island dibtrict ISO
iriilos northeast of Sltka nnd bordering
Gastcncaux channel a narrow inlet
which separates Douglass island from
the mainland the Sltka dibtrict the
quarU deposits of which nro found at
Silver Iwy n narrow tortuous arm of
the Pacific indenting BaranolT island
nnd in the valley of the Yukon river In
western Alaska. Gold bearing quart/
has albo been found nt Unga island ono
of the smaller of the Aleutian group and
SQIUO egort has been made there at de
velopment but moro of that hereafter.
-mT" At concerns the Yukon valley little at
tention 1ms boon paid by explorers nnd
prospectors to discover gold bearing
quartniul the only results bp far re
late to placer mining. At the head of
Lynn canal ono of the inner pass
ages adapted to steamer navigation
about HIM miles northeast of Sltka. Is the
ft mouth of the Ohllcatl river navigable
for canoes for n score of miles. At the
head of this canoe navigation nro three
large t'hilcatl villages and It is at this
point where commences what is known
ns the Chllcatl Portage across the range
to the head waters of the Yukon river in
British territory. The distance from
the Indian villages on the American
side of the divide to the first lake the
bource of the Yukon is about thirty
miles but the source is one of the most
dillicult in the territory yet the only
practicable ono to reach the Yukon
valley from the south. During the past
three yeatt the reports that the bars of
the Yukon and its tributaries. Stewart
and i'ellv rivers nnd Forty-Mile crook
were rich in placer gold have induced
several Alaska miners to venture across
the range at the Chllcatl crobsing and
descend these streams. Several parties
nro all known to have perished in this
perilous search for the new gold fields.
In the history of gold mining in the
states and territories no obstacle was so
stubborn that it was not finally over
come. This too will be the history oj
he tfolu" fields of western Alaska.</text>
      </result>
      <result>

	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86063615/1897-07-20/ed-1/?sp=2&q=Alaska+gold+rush&st=text&r=0.301,0.07,0.14,0.182,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>GOLD MER RAGING.
ALASICAV TfnWvS DESERTED IN THE
IILS1I l'Oll KLONDIKE.
MANY GOING WITHOUT MEANS.
MORE STOniES OF THE WEUTII
THAT II S BEEN DISCOVERED.
Captain HlKSiun, of the Excelsior,
Sa Thut Klondjke la n. Great
Place for a Man IVItU a
Icnr's Provision to
Make a StuL.e.
Port Townsend, Wash., July 19 The ex
cursion steamer Queen has arrived from
Alaska with 170 passengers, principally
tourists. Tho officers of the Queen state
that the merchants and tradesmen in both
Juneau and Sitka are closing their shops
and hastening to the new Eldorado Fifty
business men left Juneau for Daw ton City
on Julv 12, and 130 were to leave on the
16th, two das after the Queen sailed The
officers sa that by tho time tho Queen re
turns to Juneau on her return trip, nine
davs hence, there will not ba an able-bodied
man left in the town. Many men are leav
ing Juneau for tho gold fields without pro
visions or means to buy them
Tho steamer Al Kl balled for Alaska at
midnight. She carries forty horses and 1,000
sheep for Dyca, where they will be land
ed and driven across tho summit to the
Yukon vallei. Stockmen say the sheep
are the finest band ever collected off East
ern Washington ranges. They will be taken
to Circle City and Klondike and slaughter
ed. Any kind of fresh meat there sells at
50 cents per pound.
San Diego, Cal., July 19. An Interesting
letter telling of the recent trip of the
steamer Excelsior to Alaska has been writ
ten by Captain J. F. Hlggins, of the steam
er, to a friend In this city Hesajs.
"The word Klondike means Deer river,
which Is called Reindeer river on the
charts. It empties into tho Yukon fifty
miles abovo tho big river. The geographic
al position of the Junction is 76 degrees 10
minutes north latitude. 139 degrees 50 min
utes west longitude. Ronanza creek dumps
Into Klondike about two miles above the
Yukon. Eldorado is a tributary of the
Bonanza. Ther are numerous other creeks
and tributaries, the main river being 300
miles long The gold so far has been taken
from the Ronanza and Eldorado, both well
named, for the richness of the placers lz
truly marvelous. Eldorado, thirty miles
long. Is staked the whole length and as far
as worked has paid.
"As each claim Is 509 feet along the creek
bed, there is half a million to the claim.
So uniform has the output been that one
miner who has an Interest In three claims
told me that If offered his choice he would
toss up to decide. One of our passengers
who Is taking J1.000 with him has worked
100 feet of his ground and refused J200,0u0
for the remainder and confidently expects
to clean up J100.0O) nnd more. He has In a
bottle J212 from one pan of dirt. His pay
dirt while btlng washed averaged J250 an
hour to each man shoveling In Two others
of the miners who worked their own claims
cleaned up J6O0O from tho day's washing.
"There Is about fifteen feet of dirt above
DedrccK, the pay streak averaging from
four to six feet, which Is tunneled out while
the ground Is frozen Of course the ground
tal.cn out is thawed by building fires, and
when the thaw comes and water rushes In
they set their sluices and wash the dirt.
Two of our fellows thought a small bird
in the hand worth a large one In the bush
and sold their claims for Jlj.OuO, getting
JI.500 down, tho remainder to be paid In
monthly installments of J10000 each The
purchasers had no more than J3.000 paid.
They were twenty days thawing and get
ting out dirt. Then there was no water to
sluice with, but one fellow made a rocker
and in ten dais took out the J10.000 for the
first Installment. So tunneling and rotklng.
they took out J49.000 before there was water
to sluice with.
"Ot courts thebo things read like tho
story of Aladdin but fiuion is not In It</text>
      </result>
    <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1897-07-20/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Alaska+gold+rush&st=text&r=-0.267,-0.114,1.446,1.446,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>INEXHAUSTIBLE RICHES OF THE NORTHERN EL DORADO.
SEATTLE, Wash.. July 19.— The busi
ness equilibrium of Seattle was never so
disturbed as it has been by the news of the
richness of the recent Klondyke strikes.
'For forty-eight hours the telegraph offices
of this city have been thronged by people
sending messages to Eastern friends
making a request for sufficient money to
get into the new camp. The list of those
who have arranged to go includes not only
'clerks and such as work for salary, but
business and professional men of recog
nized standing and ability.
"Send me $500. Stake me enough
money to go to Klondyke. News not in
the least exaggerated," is the tenor of the
appeal flashed over the wires. Men are
t being grubstaked in tnis city to an extent
never before thought of and never before
possible. Some local bouses who are
likely to lose trustworthy and well-known
employes will be behind them in many
cases, while individual men with money
at their disposal who by reason of circum
stances cannot go are not slow to outfit
men in whom they can place unbounded
confidence.
Many amusing instances connected with
grubstakes are transpiring.- One which
will actually describe the situation had
its finale this morning early. A well
known man, honest but poor, was one of
the first stricken with the desire to go.
The information reached a friend Satur
day afternoon and shortly after the two
met. "How much do you want?" in
quired No. 2 of the Klondyke fever pa
tient. "I think about $400," was the re
spon-e. "bee me in the morning; I think
I can stake you." Sunday the two did
not meet, but early this morning they
did,, when No. 2 gave the first man a chill
that extended down the vertebra^ to the
end of his toes. "I guess that matter is j
all off," No. 2 said. "I have about decided
to go myself, and my man who is inter- 1
ested with me is also going."
It must be said that meanwhile noth-
ing is occurring which in the least de-
j tracts or discredits tho Monte Cristo-like
tales first sent out from the district. Sub- j
sequent reports not only verify but tend to
enlarge upon the first accounts. Hon.
C. H. Macintosh, Governor of the North
west Territory, comprising the districts of
j Alberta, Saskatchewan, Assinniboia and
the unorganized districts of the Yukon, i
Athabasca and all the territory east to
Labrador and Hudson Bay, arrived in j
Seattle' to-day, being en route to Regina,
the capital of tha Territory. He was seen
at the Rainier CluD.of which he is a guest,
this afternoon. When asked for an ex
pression of his views regarding the great
Klondyke district Governor Macintosh
replied:
"We are only on the threshold of the
greatest discovery 'ever made. Gold has
been piling up in all -these innumerable
streams for hundreds of years. Much of
the territory the, foot of man has .never
trod. It would hardly be possible for one
jySS exaggerate tee richness, hot only of the
Klondyke, but other districts in the Cana-
dian«"Yukon. At the same time the folly
of thousands rushing in there without I
proper means of subsistence and in utter
ignorance of the geographical conditions j
1 of the country should be kept ever in
mind. There are fully 9000 miles of these
i golden waterways in this section of the
Yukon. Rivers, creeks and streams of i
l every size and description are all pos- I
"sessed of more or less gold. I derived this j
knowledge from many old Hudson Bay
explorers, who assured me that they con
sidered the gold-bearing district next to
_ inexhaustible.
"In 1894 I made a report to Sir John
Thompson, then Premier of Canada, and
who died the same year at Windsor
Castle, strongly urging that the name
Yukon should be given to that country
by order in council and that a body of
Canadian police be established on the
river to maintain order. This was done j
j in 1&05 and the British outpost of Fort
Cudahy was founded. I have known gold
to exist there since 1889 consequent upon
a report made me by W. Ogilvie, the j
Government explorer.
Many of "-/hat will no doubt prove to be
as rich or richer streams than the Klon- i
dyke have not been explored or pros- I
pected. Among these I might mention
Dominion Creek, Hootalinqua River,
Stewart River, Liard River and a score of j
other streams comparatively unknown. j
It is my judgment and opinion that the
1897 yield of the Canadian Yukon will ex- i
ceed $10,000,000 in gold. Of course as is
the case of the Cariboo and Cassiar dis- I
tricts years ago, it will be impossible to
accurately estimate the full amount taken
out. There is now far in excess of $1,000,
--000 remaining already mined on the Klon
dyke. It is in valises and tin cans and
some of it is lying loose in saloons and
just as sacredly guarded there and appa
rently as safe as though it was in vaults.
"Already this spring we have official
knowledge of, over $2,000,000 in gold
having been taken out of the Klondyke j
THE YUKON ORDER OF PIONEERS— McQuestin, the Father of the Camp, Sits in the
Middle, With Frank Bowker, Who Has $90,003 in Gold Dost, on the Righ^
The San Francisco Call
Official Verification of the Wonderful Gold Discoveries in the Klondyke j
District Ten Million Dollars a Conservative Estimate of What
Will Be Taken Out This Year.
camps. It was shipped out, as you know, j
on the steamers Excelsior ana Portland.
Let me cite a little incident or an instance t
shewing the gold yield of some of the j
Klondyke claims. A friend of mine went j
to a dump and was looking it over, and lie j
told me that it bore the appearance of
some ones having taken and poured j
bucketfuls of gold nuggets down over the
dump. In truth, he said there appeared
to be more gold than dust. Incidentally*
I may say to you that we have data of an j
official nature which leads us to believe i
ttiat the gold output for the Rossland and
Kootenay districts for 1397 will be in excess j
of $7,000,000, including the silver yield I j
should have said, and I have no hesitancy j
in asserting that within the course of five I
years the gold yield of the three districts j
named will exceed that of either Colorado,
California or South Africa."
Governor Macintosh announced that I
the Government is seriously considering i
the construction of a railroad into the I
Yukon district. In fact, he said, it has
several corns of engineers now making
surveys.
"One route," the Governor said, "con- i
templates the operation of a line of steam
ers from Fort Wrangel up the Stickeem
R ver, which Is open to both countries,
under the Washington treaty of some
twenty-five years ago, to Telegraph Creek.
From Telegraph Creek surveyors are now
endeavoring to ascertain the feasibility of
the construction of a railway line from j
125 to 130 miles to Teslin Lake. The route
extends through scrubby timber, and has
only one or two serious obstacles. Begin-
ning with Teslin Lake, boats will be oper- j
ated along a series of lakes and rivers that j
connect with the Stewart and Pelly rivers
emptying into the Yukon. It is claimed
that no serious difficulties, that is diffi-
culties such as cannot be reasonably over- j
come, are encountered anywhere along
this route.
"1 may say in this connection that tbe
route I have just described to you would
be more than 3000 miles shorter than the
present route by way of Sl Michaels and
the YuKon and every foot of it would be
in British territory. There is another
route through Canada which has been
found possible. A railway extends from j
Calgary, Northwest Territory, over 200
miles. Then there is a trail, and a good j
one, from Edmonton to Athabasca, land
ing in the unorganized district of Atha- j
basca.* Hudson Bay boats how run over
.Athabasca La k.* down slit river of Atha- j
basca to the vicinity of McKenzie River,
where it has' been found possible with
very easy portages to reach the Porcupine
River, and thence down that stream into
the' Yukon. The Government explorer, j
Mr. Ogilvie, made an inspection of this
route several times, once in 1887. once in
1888 and in 1890 and 1891 with Mr. j
Dawson, the director-general of geological j
surveys. The White horse River route is J
also considered feasible."
The Governor leaves in the morning for I
Victoria, going thence to his capital. Re- j
gina. He comes here in reality to see one j
of his sons, who has the fever, safely off
to the Klondyke.
Discussing the Stikeem River route the j
Alaska Mining Record of Juneau in the i
issue of July 14 says:</text>
      </result>
      <result>

	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030272/1896-03-01/ed-1/?sp=28&q=Alaska+gold+rush&st=text&r=-0.172,-0.067,1.344,1.344,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>r I THE RUSH TO THE YUKON I
t i ZnOlllHCrS or A mo ciioii IN
j i k run GREAT VZACER nzqriixos
0
0f Xi rtlH In I iTnneau PripBtlat to Tackle the
t j BelRe About the Middle of March One
Immallr Knrlj HurtHaw to Get Into
t r the llmln Reqalrementi of n Froiipeetor
i Htorlen from the Alaska lnalnc
z il W JUNEAU Alaska Feb OThe rush Into tho
tI t Yukon has already begun The first party of
minors t tko tho trail lot Juncaii about tlio
1 middle of January There wore nine men lu
tho party Thin Is I nn nnuitinlly early start
for miners Ao many othera In town nro
I r getting ready for the trip Intending t tacklo
b tho range about tho middle of March Every
g Htcamer that come In from below now brings
I r n party of oldtimers and crowds of now mel
i r all anxious t Ret In and Ret to work Tho
it t Yukon country In II mot certain to bo over
1 crowded this summer surly as regards winter
t supplies unlosa largo outfits nro taken In from
t hero b tho minors
t i I From all accounts received her from BOO
4 tlons along the PaclOo coast and In the Kant
Alaska I f destined to receive a rush of people
this summer which will not bo consistent
rl t I with tho present progress and tho amount of
c4 work nowgolqg on Alaska at present ran
k support 8 many people and no more and If
I the rush pans out according t present pros
pects there Is likely to bo cons lerablo hard
Wi hip Alaska has no Industries except mining
i I nt which tho wage earner can make a decent
I 1 livelihood and unless a man has cuflldont
t meang to carry him through either In soma
Il t business orfor a seasons prospeetnl ho had
Js letter steer clear of this country It reouin
t omo capital l IUi prospect foru a mining claim
f1 I and when tho claim Isfound It requires more
f capital t open It up Gold nuggets do not
grow on bushes and It takes both 1 mans
I hands and his rockets to get tho low metal
ln this country Theres an almighty lot of
I 4t here but It Isnt to b had for tho asking
It Is perhaps timely now to tell something
t explicit about tho way of getting Into tho Yu
t kon and tho difficulties of tho trip Xo ono
should think of coming to Alaska who has not
perfect health and has not moreover u more
than ordinarily strong constitution to enable
I lilm t withstand the atmospheric nnd cllniatlo
changes In tho Yukon district tho thcrmom
ictcrhas an annual range of 180 Thcro Is a
f time In tho short summer when It ranges about
I 110 above zero and In tho winter it frequent
LII jy goes t 70 below and sometimes more
I 9 I J No ono should como to Alaska who has not
1 omo practical knowledge of quartz and placer
t
1 mining Theories nro all rlaht In their
I way and tbo theorist may stumble upon
f5 something good but It Is tho practical
prospector who gets tho Alaskan nug
Lti gets every time Every unfavorable re
i j port of Alaska mines can b traced directly I to
d seine disappointed tenderfoot who thought he
ti I could como up hero and pick the gold olf the
1 Imshes Most of them didnt like it because
i 11 they found they couldnt get nuggets as easily
f II us they could salmon berries Anybody can
I tell uold after tho smelter gets through with
It but It Isnt to easy to know where to lok
F I tor and how to timid It
I you are contemplating making the trip
I f Into tho Yukon you want t give careful confederation
i I I federation to theso thing Tho length of tlmo
t you will have to stay In tho country tho
I pmount of money It will take and tho results I
i I I which may bo attained liriefly these things
are Tlmo tlirco years money SOO roo
suits unlimited Little can b accomplished
t In less than three years stay In the Yukon
V unless tho prospector has marvelous good
luck A good part of tho first season will b
consumed In reaching tho mines Then If u
I claim Is discovered and located only prelimi
nary work can bo clone The second year tho
i claim can b opened up well and probably
I y otte money can b mado Tho third year Is
I when IH6 prospector may reasonably expect to
I I get his profits
No man ought t make tho start Into the Yu
kon basin with loss than S300 above what ho
expects t spend for the outfit which shall carry
I him through to tho diggings That Is if ho goes
In by way of Juneau and over tho pass ho wants
I to havo SiOO when ho gets to Forty Mile or
Circle City or wherever It Is he Is going I
I lie goes by the way of St Michaels and up tho
Yukon ho wants to have just the same money
Tlie read Is a long ono whichever way ho goes
t Supplies are expensive The season Is short and
fortune Is fickle Failure to find cold the first
I I lon Is likely to entail great hardship upon
L those whoso funds mire Insufficient at tho start
m Not one In a hundn makei u paying strike
the first ncnson iho trading companies In
k the Interior find market for
Ind a quick mlrkot all their
I I goods at spot nth pi ices all they refuse Ibo
I lutcly to give rf lrce Their supoly Is almost
I Invariably behind the demand These aro the
I coldblooded facts and If you havent got time
money to meot them VOlt hud better not try to
ro Into the Yukon bn in looking for a fortune
I You wont get I Hut I vouve got the money
and If yoU ore strong nud healthy and ambi
tious and aro n prm tleul prospector and If
youve got pood grit why come along Heres
tho i lace where you can make a pile Thems
I lots of It up here and such men are digging it
out every jear I Is I estimated that they dug
out In t le Yukon district In tho lust season
II upward nf SHOOOOO and that isnt a patch 01
wnats there
p I The great basin of the Yukon Is reached
I practically by hut one rcnite that by I way of
t Juneau and tho Chltkoot Pass Tills Is tho
ehcrtest quickest and cheapest route and
i the ono taken bv fully on per cent of the
J r gold seekers of tho Interior The first hun</text>
      </result>

    <result>
	    <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1898-04-09/ed-1/?sp=8&q=Alaska+gold+rush&st=text&r=-0.026,0.392,0.581,0.581,0</id>
	    <rel>1</rel>
	    <text>JUNEAT', Alaska. April 4 (by steam-
Bhip Al-Ki, via Seattle, April B).— A
horrible catastrophe, surpassing in the
number of fatalities the flooding of the
canyon last fall by the mountain lake,
nas occurred in Dyea Canyon, between
Sheep Camp and the Scales. An ava
lanche of snow and ice yesterday after
aoon swooped down the mountain,
burying alive and crushing between
forty and fifty men, and injuring nearly
is many more. There is great excite
ment as Skaguay and Dyea, and many
will leave here for the scene of the dis
ister on the steamship Australia, which
sails late f>-night for Skaguay. The
srst news of the calamity reached here
at 5 o'clock this afternoon on th»
Bteamship Discovery and the Al-Ki
came in at about 8 o'clock to-night and
;onfirmed the report.
The Al-Ki left Skaguay at 9:30 this
morning. As the fatal snow slide oc
curred at about 4 o'clock yesterday
(Sunday) afternoon only meager details
were obtainable here to-night. The
representative of The Cah whom I left
In charge at Skaguay and Dyea during
my absence chartered a tug at Skag
uay last evening to take him around
the point to Dyea and from there he
will go by horse to the place of death.
I will reach the scene to-morrow after
noon.
A telephone message was received at
Skaguay from Dyea late last night,
stating that twenty-seven bodies had
been dug out of the snow. A large force
of volunteers is at work with pick and
shovel throwing aside the snow in the
hope that it may be in time to rescue
Borne of the buried men alive. The res
cuers worked all night.
About 8 o'clock this morning another
message came by telephone from Dyea
stating that eighteen more bodies
had been excavated. If these figures
are accurate they will make a total of
forty-three dead.
The slide occurred in about the same
place where the lake of water broke
loose last fall. It was near Stone
House and over on the other side of the
canyon. John Pellett of Seattle, a pas
senger on the Discovery, left Sheep
Camp yesterday morning, a few hours
before the snow slide. He said:
"The first we heard of the accident
was last evening at Skaguay. The re
port came over from Dyea by tele
phone. I left Sheep Camp early yes
terday morning to catch the first boat
south. It had been snowing steadily
for two days up the canyon. It was a
heavy, wet snow. Great quantities of
It accumulated on the mountain sides,
and I expected some of it to fall down.
There was so much snow that I did not
Bee how it could cling to the sides of the
canyon. Great fields and mountains of
It were piled upon the top of the can
yon on both sides. There are tents and
camps all along the canyon. The men
gx» up loaded early in the morning and
come back to their camp or cache at
Sheep Camp at 11 or 12 o'clock. In the
afternoon they make another trip to
the summit or the Scales, and along
about 4 o'clock and on to 5 o'clock there
j- r*Kular crocession of men cominir
bark on the trail. That explains to me
why so many were caught and buried.
"The walls of the canyon opposite
Stone House are almost perpendicular.
A man would have only one chance In
a hundred of petting out of the way
of an avalanche there, even If he
looked up and saw It earning. It would
be a straight fall Instead of a slide. I
heard that thirty-one dead men were
taken out last night."
A little more light Is thrown on the
disaster by the situation of the trails
at Stone House. The horse trail runs
to the right of the canyon, going up
and over close to Stone House. Foot
and handsled trail Is over on th~ op
posite side and follows the course of
the river, which is considerably lower
than the horse trail, and all day Ions?
there are twenty men on the hand
sled trail to one on the horse trail. I
have seen 100 men on this trail within
a distance of fifty yards, going and
coming. Nearly opposite Stone House,
on the brow of the canyon, is a glacier.
Its walls of ice, beautiful as emerald
and sapphire in' the sunshine, an im
aginary cathedral of the skies, stand
exposed in June as well as in January-
It does not melt away the y?ar round.
Mountains of snow crown this glacier
during the winter. This is the point
from which the avalanche came.
A small snow slide which occurred
shortly before the big avalanche buried
two or three men who were encampc-d
along the trail. While those on the trail
were hard at work endeavoring to ex
tricate the unfortunates the monster
avalanche swept down the mountain
side, crushing the tents pitched along
the trail and enveloping scores of men,
the majority of whom were endeavoring
to assist those who had met with mis
fortune in the previous smaller slide.
The injured gold-seekers who have
been rescued are terribly lacerated, and
it is feared that a number of them will
die. As soon as the news of the calam
ity was made known along the trail
men hurried to the scene from Dyea
and other points, and with shovels,
picks and even pans and pails toiled
to extricate the unfortunates. Sheep
Camp was soon left without an inhabi
tant, as every one from there to the
scales was soon on the scene.
The sight was an awful one, for there
in a state of terrible excitement, which
increased as the bodies were uncovered,
were brothers, fathers, sons and friends
anxiously digging, trembling lest the
next body they uncovered should. be
that of a loved one. As in the rush to
the gold fields, but few men, even
though traveling together, went to the
trouble of inquiring as to the names
of their companions, the greater num
ber of the dead have not been Identi
fied, and those who have been taken
out alive are so benumbed and dazed
that they can hardly tell who had been
in company with them.
The roar of the avalanche could be
distinctly heard at Sheep Camp and as
far as Canyon City, situated about six
miles south of the fatal spot.
Seventeen men. all members of the
Chilkoot Transportation Company,
started over the trail on Sunday morn
ing and had about time to reach the
Scales when the terrible slide occurred.
None of them have since been seen,
and none of their bodies have been re
covered. It Is feared the entire party
was caught in the slide and killed.
There were a good many tents covered
up beyond the reach of rescuers and
numbers of bodies will never be re
covered until the spring sun thaws
away their snow graves.</text>
    </result>


            <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85038615/1905-04-02/ed-1/?sp=31&q=Alaska+gold+rush&r=-0.335%2C0.126%2C1.406%2C0.916%2C0&st=text</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>PRICE FIVE CENTS
rwn HRILLING and MlMBfis tlie call
M now being trumpeted'byTatiana, the
Eldorado in Alaska.' Already thou?
sands of frenzied seekers after gold are there.
"For fortunes beyond the dreams of.ava
rice are being garnered by placer mines along
the streams in that locality.
As much as $ioo a pan has.been washed
out in this new district. How startling these
figures are to miners may be judged from'the
fact that, ground averaging 40 cents to the
pan is considered a bonanza, and ip cents a
pan is regarded as big pay.
During the last winter, in spite of the
fact that the ground was frozen, one claim
averaged $1000 in pay dirt a day, and a num?
ber of claims changed hands at $60,000 each.
Within the last twelve months 4000
miners from the Klondike have rushed to the
new fields.* They were the first to hear the
news. All durW.g the winter hundreds strug?
gled thither over snow and ice. Indications
point to a remarkable rush northward from
Seattle this string.
Fairbanks, the centre of the Tatiana
region, consisted a year ago of a few log
cabins. To-day it is a prosperous city of over
three thousand people, with all the conven?
iences of modern city life.
AS SOON as boats are able to navigato the
inland streams of Alaska, a great summer
rush to Tanana is expected to begin. Re?
ports from Seattle state that gold-seekers
aro crowding therj from all parts of the country.
A surprisingly large number are outfitting as
though they had been in mining regions beforo nnd
knew how to arrange for the long and tiresomo trip
by steamer, dog team and afoot. 1
Freight charges from Seattle to Dawson in
eummer average over $7d a tori, and as much moro
from .Dawson to Fairbanks, so that the cost of tak?
ing along an extensive equipment is considerable.
It is estimated that the Tanana region pro?
duced $1,500,000 in gold last year, when tho num?
ber of miners was insignificant, compared with the
great army that will camp alonar its streams this
season.
Before news of tho rich'finds penetrated beyond
,the silent forests, pioneer prospeotorj had quietly
taken out a quarter of a million in yellow metal
flakes.
Until the new trails were broken aud in use,
Tanana was not an easy section of Alaska to reach
or leave, and travelers along that way wero scarce?
consisting principally of Indians hunting game or
stray prospectors nosing about for gold.
Situated on tho Tanana river, tho town of
Fairbanks is 150 miles southeast of tho point of
juncture pf that river with'the mighty Yukon; Daw
eon, in the Klondike, is 500 miles away to the oast
ward by sledgo trail, and to the south Valdez, on
the coast, is 5?i miles distant.
Discoverers of gold along tho Tanana wore not
inclined to shout tho glad tidings to the world.
Among those patiently .washing dift there dur?
ing the fall of 1002 wa*'a secretivo individual, a
Mexican, known as Pedro,
Pedro, like the others, lived in a little hut. His
bed was a blanket; chairs and table Avere simply
blocks of -wood. He had little use for the cabin, ex?
cept as a placo to sleep and store his provisions.
All the long arctic days ?ho searched soil along
the streams for gold, usually alone in the vast wil?
derness. At other places w? re other men'similarly
engaged, but they, too, were'there for business and
had little time for sociability.
Ono day Pedro made" a big strike. Ho found
gold that turned out $100 to, the. pan. Pedro was
a rich man. Then he went away to the couth. But
he didn't spread the news-?he was faithful to tho
miners left behind.
Others, too, were lucky. Stray prospectors
came that Avay andimmediately'located claims.- It
seemed as if somo had smelled the good news from
distant camps.,
For months this handful of men struggled
fiercely to wash all the gold they could before tho
mad rush they knew was coming, sooner or later.
First to arrivo Avere some steamboat men Avho
had ascended the river with supplies for tho trading,
post just opened at Fairbanks. These men heard
of the marvelous new field and promptly staked
claims there.
Among them was an energetic Japanese named
Wada, Avho, like others of his race, had been in
many mining camps of the far North.
For some reason, as soon as ho had ctaked his
claim and learned of the richness of the region,
Wada started out on a long, lono tramp over the
snow, with a dog team drawing his ipplies, for
Dawson) BOO mi lea away.
No trail liad been broken -or at least half the
distanco, butWada. plunged along, helping the dogs
and Making from fifteen to twenty-five inilos a day.
He wns tho first to bear the news of Tanana'a
wealth to Bawsou, and minors of the older Klondike
region immediately Avent wild.
This was in the Avintor of.lOO'i?an exception?
ally cold season, even in Alaska.
Without waiting for spring, -.rimers hurried off
in hundreds for a 6U0-mile journey over snow and
ice, and through a.roadless -yilderness, in a tem?
perature from 50 to CO degreed below ?ero.
Hastily authoring what supplies thoy could,
some left Bawson in small sleighs drawn by horses,
others with ?log teams; but the greater number
hurried along on foot, drawing their sleda them-,
'selves.
It was a mad rush for g?ld^:3ir?ny.reached tha
?new field before spring, ?but hundreds of others
came'toiling in all during tho sunom?f.
"When the majority arrived thoy, found the best
claims'already taken, a shortago of, supplies facing
them, and discouragement in tho air.
Wada had returned with the rush. When some
of the men realized their position, they brga?niged'
a miners' meeting and decided to hang the' Jap.
A rope Avas found, and Wada was about to be
strung tip, when ho produced a copy ?f a Seattle
newspaper, showing that he had onco saved the
lives of many whalers, ico-impriaoned in the Arctic
Ocean by tramping overland from Point Barrow to,
St. Michael in dead of winter.
This saved his life, but "Wada Avas driven from
the region to which he had invited tho rush.
In spite of their first disappointment, tho new?
comers spread out and set to work. At this time
gold was only known to exist along one creek. Soon
it" was found along a dozen creek's.
In the spring tho rush from Bawson continued
by steamboat. Olairas were located in overy direc?
tion. Now hundreds who arrived late, or Avho found
that thoir claims did not pay, ar.o working as labor?
ers for tho moro fortunate.
In a little Avhilo, too, all thb surface gold had
been panned, so that it became noces?ary to work
the underground strata by machinery.
When'tha Klondike Avaa struck, the only method
known of thawing the frozen ground for sinking
ehafta and running tunnela was to build Avood fires
on the surface, scrapo away the earth as far as it
had thawed, build other fires and keep this tedious
process up indefinitely.</text>
      </result>


    <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90059523/1899-10-15/ed-1/?sp=21&q=Alaska+gold+rush&st=text&r=-0.275,-0.078,1.551,1.551,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>ST. MICHAELS, Alaska, Sopt. 15.—
The most remarkable gold mining at
present In the world, if not in the entire
history of gold mining, is that now in
progress at and about Cape Nome, on
Norton Sound, Behring Sea, Alaska, sit
uated about 225 miles north and west
of the mouth of the Yukon river, or 135
miles from this point. Gold was first dis
covered on Snake river last fail, and
during the earlier portion of this season.
Cape Nome district had acquired con
siderable repute as a gold producer, and
not a few miners from the Yukon river
f Lx r\* rfi^*?--.".^rrT _/^ t 1" "^"^/^^^=k_.^^\!l\ V V S"^'^
new v ?^p. A^f,
MAP SHOWING LOCATION OF THE GOLDEN SANDS, AND ILLUSTRATING METHODS OF THE MINERS.
country, many of them stranded here,
f went over to Nome and either staked
such claims as they could get, or secured
work as they could find It. Much com
plaint was made that claims had been
taken by persons holding powers of at
torney, their principals not being present
in person, and in June the Cape Nome
district had become so unpopular 'hat
reports were circulating to the effect that
the whole thing was a "fake" foisted on
the public by the transportation compa
nies to Improve their business.
Whatever of truth there may have been
In these stories Is now of small import,
for in June or early July, some one of
the stranded miners tenting on the beach,
as the only unclaimed space, accidentally
discovered gold in the sand at his feet.
He told his story quickly among his
stranded friends, and soon all the unem
ployed were at work on the beach with
any and all kinds of tools that would
dig. Their success was such that within
a few days men who had work on
claims along the creek at $10 a day and
board threw up their jobs and took to
the beach, expecting to earn, and actual
ly earning in many instances, as much in
an hour as they had earned in a day.
Never had such easy mining brnn heard
Df, never had it been found so unex
pectedly and so opportunely, and it was
•lot long before everything else was 2
serted for the seashore, and even wo
olen and boys of 10 or 12 years were to bo
found as busy in the sand as the men
were.
Since the discovery the number of j
"beach combers," as they are called, has I
steadily increased, and today is presented
the strange' sight of hundreds of miners I
rof both sexes and all ages and condl-
".ions strung out along the beach for a
rlozen miles or more.
For miles to the west of Cape Nome the
oeach runs straight away In a strip of
;lde land, varying from forty to sixty
!eet in width between high and low water
mark, extending up to the "tundra" cr
black alluvial soil, which is from three
to five feet higher than the beach proper.
All of this tundra, ard all the territory
along the creeks and rivers east and west j
for thirty or forty miles and back into j
the mountains for ten or twelve miles had
been staked, but on the long strip of tide i
lands no man had a better claim than j
another, or could have, under the tide-
land laws, and here the grand army of
gold seekers camped, and in very short
order had converted the barren strand
Into a site of tremendous and enthusiastic
Industry. At the same time business of
all kinds began to respond to the boom
i from the beach, and the usual collection
of gambling hells, saloons and dance
halls went Into operation. At present it
t ls estimated that 1,000 to 1,200 miners are
at work on the beach, extending west for
twenty miles. All these work with rock
_ ers, and they occupy just as much ter
ritory to the man or group as can work
It It is not unusual for one small square
bit of beach to pan out $10 to $15 an hour,
but, of course, the space is soon exhaust
ed and the lucky digger must move to
another snot.
This beach deposit of gold Is as yet
an unsolved problem. By some It Is claim
ed that the gold In the sand, which is
entirely "dust," has been washed out
from the tundra by the waves at high
tide and deposited through hundreds of
years in the sand. It is found here now
from two to five feet below the surface In
the drift, and so plentiful that the miner
who does not find It In paying quantities
is the exception. On the other hand,
there are some who claim that the gold
is washed in from the sea, and that the
real field or "mother lode," so to speak.
Is to be reached and developed by dredg
ing. There may be something in this
theory, but the other seems to be the
more tenable, "-.ark'jpi^eya^fa^
The beach to the east of Cape Nome
makes no such gold showing as does the
beach to the west, owing to the existence
of a long reach of water or "lagoon,"
which lies a short distance back from
the sea and parallel with It. Gold deposits
along the creeks the interior are quite
as rich In one direction as the other.
The headquarters of the Cape Nome
territory is Anvil City—so named from
the shape" of the mountain above It—at
the mouth of Snake river, although Nome
City is the postofflce. While the city pos
sesses a number of frame houses, tents
are the prevailing shelter, and prices for
commodities are pretty much as they are
In all mining towns. Notwithstanding
this is one of the most' accessible mining
towns on earth, as ships from any part
of the world may come up to its very
doors, making due allowances for no har
bor, and -much delay between ship and
shore in bad weather. Meals are from
•$1.50 to $2.50 each; a bed In a tent, $1.50;
plain drinks, 50 cents each; beer, 50 cents
per glass, and other things in proportion,
including a mutton chop at $I.2s—and, by
the way, these are not much in excess of
prices at first-class places ln New York
city. Copper plate for use In rockers is
worth Its weight In silver, and one miner
who had no copper substituted silver dol
lars for It, sixty-four of them being re
quired to properly plate his rocker, which,
added to the first cost of $20, made it
somewhat expensive, even for this local
ity. Labor in the mines Is worth from $8
to $10 a day and board, and even carpen
ters, about the only other class of labor,
are paid $1.50 and hour and board them
selves. As the days In summer are from
eighteen to twenty-four, hours long, a
carpenter can put In a lot of spare time.
Everybody has money, and as many who
have It are not used to It, they are lav
ishing their earnings by day on gambling,
liquor and dance halls at night. Gam
bling takes the bulk of the dust, and
every species of game is represented in
Anvil City.
As to what amount of geld is being
taken out, there Is no means of determin
ing. It is known that not more than $200,
--000 in all have been shipped by steamer,
and $100,000 of that has gone out within
the past week. The beach mining is re
ported to be turning out about $30,000 a
day, but this in the nature of things can
not continue, and when it is exhausted
these men will go to work on the numer
ous claims lying back from the sea and
along the creeks. Here the gold is found
In very rich deposits, the claim of Linde
burg- Co., on Anvil Creek, turning out
over $1,000 an hour ($25,000 in twenty-four
hours),. one nugget recently found being
worth $312. Another claim, owned by Dr.
Kettlesen, in one day cleared* up $9,000,
and so the stories go. One may hear al
most any kind of a fairy tale, and while
some cf them are exaggerated the fact
remains that just now every man in the
district has a pocket full of dust and
heart full of hope, and there are no dead
brokes In- Anvil City. "What the condi
tions will be a year hence will not be
known until then, and cannot be pre
dicted.
Nov. 1 communication with the outside
world will be completely shut off for sev
en month's at least, and only a few of
(he people now in the Cape Nome district
are fixed with either food or shelter for
the sever!- of the climate, though those
who are prepared with houses to live in
and sufficient food and fuel can not only'
pass the winter comfortably, but can do
more or less work.
There are very few so well eff as this,
however, fuel being scarcer than food,
but among the "beach combers" a novel
plan will be adopted. Parties of four,
six or eight will organize for winter op
erations by securing a large tent, spread
ing ii over the ground they propose to
work In, and there they, will set up house
keeping. The canvas will.be protected on
the outside from the weather in every
way possible, and stoves will be kept go
ing on the inside, so that the tent will not
only be comfortable to live and to work
in, but it will never freeze in there, and
the mining can go on quite as satisfac
torily as if the balmy spring were the
only season known in tho Cape Nome dis
trict A groat rush is expected in the
spring, but, as has been stated, there are
no claims unstaked anywhere within
thirty or forty miles of Anvil City, and
what lies beyond those limits is pracfical
ly unknown. But, according to the tales
of prospectors, as far beyond as Cape
Prince of "Wales, 2:*5 miles, gold has been
found along the creaks in quantities that
would pay from $10 to $50 per man par
day if panned by an expert.
Claims are offered for sale—a claim be
ing twenty acres—at prices from $50,000
to $150,000, and there are, of course, at
this time not many takers at those, fig
ures, but they are expected In the spring
with the rush.</text>
      </result>

# manually search
    <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

    <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>


          <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>


          <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>


          <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

    </results>
  </topic>

  <topic>
    <id></id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>

  <topic>
    <id></id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>
